<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 Exegetical and Philosophical Traditions ∵ on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/2_Exegetical_and_Philosophical_Traditions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 Exegetical and Philosophical Traditions ∵ on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/2_Exegetical_and_Philosophical_Traditions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>4 Rāmakaṇṭha 0 Ātman Debate</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/2_Exegetical_and_Philosophical_Traditions/4_rAmakaNTha_0_Atman_Debate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/2_Exegetical_and_Philosophical_Traditions/4_rAmakaNTha_0_Atman_Debate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Further Thoughts on Rāmakaṇṭha’s Relationship to Earlier Positions in the Buddhist-Brāhmaṇical Ātman Debate&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alex Watson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The present article is a continuation of my previous work on where precisely to place Rāmakaṇṭha’s self-theory (ātmavāda) in the nexus of other rival posi tions. I am delighted to have been included in this volume and in the con ference which led to it, in honour of my former DPhil supervisor, Profes sor Alexis Sanderson, with whom I spent many hours reading Rāmakaṇṭha’s Nareśvaraparīkṣāprakāśa (as well as Kumārila’s Ślokavārttika, ātmavāda, and Vasubandhu’s Abhidharmakośabhāṣya, pudgalaviniścaya)—and indeed at whose suggestion I began working on Rāmakaṇṭha’s philosophical texts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Some Hitherto Unknown Fragments of</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/2_Exegetical_and_Philosophical_Traditions/5_Some_Hitherto_Unknown_Fragments_of/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/2_Exegetical_and_Philosophical_Traditions/5_Some_Hitherto_Unknown_Fragments_of/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Utpaladeva’s Vivṛti (II): Against the Existence of External Objects&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Isabelle Ratié&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Fragments of Utpaladeva’s Vivṛti in Marginal Annotations of Manuscripts Belonging to the Pratyabhijñā Corpus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Raffaele Torella’s discovery and remarkable edition of the only (and very incomplete) manuscript of the Vivṛti thus far known1 has enabled us to deter mine with certainty that some marginal annotations in manuscripts of Abhi navagupta’s Īśvarapratyabhijñāvimarśinī (henceforth ĪPV) and Īśvarapratya bhijñāvivṛtivimarśinī (henceforth ĪPVV) regularly quote Utpaladeva’s lost work. Nine of the ĪPV manuscripts that I have been able to consult contain such quotations;2 two ĪPVV manuscripts3 known to me bear several fragments, the most important of which is by far the lengthiest Vivṛti fragment known to date (including the one found in the codex unicus edited by Raffaele Torella), covering three Vivṛti chapters;4 and two manuscripts of the Īśvarapratyabhi jñāvṛtti (henceforth Vṛtti) have been shown to contain some much shorter Vivṛti quotations.5 The following pages are an attempt to edit and translate&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Alchemical Metaphors for Spiritual Transformation in Abhinavagupta’s Īśvarapratyabhijñāvimarśinī and Īśvarapratyabhijñāvivṛtivimarśinī</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/2_Exegetical_and_Philosophical_Traditions/6_Alchemical_Metaphors_for_Spiritual_Transformatio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/2_Exegetical_and_Philosophical_Traditions/6_Alchemical_Metaphors_for_Spiritual_Transformatio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Christopher D. Wallis&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a great privilege to be able to present a paper in honour of Alexis G.J.S. San derson. I was fortunate enough to be his pupil for two years at Oxford, and to study with him subsequently in Leipzig and Kyoto. In my view, if one were to accord Professor Sanderson the praise that he in fact merits, it would sound (to those who do not know him) like embarrassingly unrestrained hyperbole. Suffice it to say here that his example formed my ideal of intellectual integrity, an ideal which entails relentless pursuit of the truth as part of a community of scholars engaged in the kind of longitudinal study that prioritizes the field as a whole over personal glory. Professor Sanderson taught me the value of admit ting when I don’t know, of sacrificing my own agenda in deference to the truth, and of striving to be as transparent a mediator as possible in the act of trans mitting the words and ideas of the ancient Sanskrit thinkers to students of the present day. It is with enormous gratitude to his unstinting scholarly labours (I estimate he has logged well over a hundred thousand hours of research so far) that I offer this paper in his honour.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 On Vāgīśvarakīrti’s Influence in Kashmir and among the Khmer</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/2_Exegetical_and_Philosophical_Traditions/7_On_vAgIshvarakIrtis_Influence_in_Kashmir_and_amo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/2_Exegetical_and_Philosophical_Traditions/7_On_vAgIshvarakIrtis_Influence_in_Kashmir_and_amo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Péter-Dániel Szántó&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The aim of this article is to point out the far-reaching influence of an East Indian tantric Buddhist scholar, Vāgīśvarakīrti ( floruit early 11th c.). In the first part I will show that his views were considered important enough to be con tested sometime before 1057ce, probably still during his scholarly activity, in Kashmir. In the second part I wish to propose the hypothesis that although unnamed, he is a master alluded to with great reverence on the Sap Bāk inscrip tion from the Khmer Empire, dated 1067ce.*&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Reflections on the King of Ascetics (Yatirāja): Rāmānuja in the Devotional Poetry of Vedānta Deśika</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/2_Exegetical_and_Philosophical_Traditions/8_Reflections_on_the_King_of_Ascetics_yatirAja_rAm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/2_Exegetical_and_Philosophical_Traditions/8_Reflections_on_the_King_of_Ascetics_yatirAja_rAm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Srilata Raman&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ocean of Śrīvaiṣṇava literature is vast and it is a humbling scholarly endeav or to realize that the more one works on it, the more there is to discover; thus, any conclusions that one reaches on the intellectual history of the tradition can only be tentative postulations which can and must be superseded by further research.1 This being said, it has become increasingly clear that we are see ing a particularly fertile period between Rāmānuja (traditional dates: CE1017– 1137CE) and Vedānta Deśika (traditional dates: CE1268–1369CE): a period when doctrinal ideas are emerging from a wide spectrum of genres—from devotional poetry and hagiographies to commentaries and kāvya literature. We see also that, for instance, when it comes to the issue of the salvational means—the upāya for mokṣa—and their definitions, there was in fact much variation and a spectrum of views, without one single overarching version. Thus, to take one example, even within what emerged as a consensus on the significance of pra patti as the more appropriate upāya for the Kali Yuga, as opposed to bhakti, matters were by no means settled in the immediate post-Rāmānuja period as to how to understand the qualifications (aṅgas) for prapatti, or who was qual ified for it.2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
