<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nepal trika survival</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/articles/nepal-trika-survival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/articles/nepal-trika-survival/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;4.Why I am in love with Nepal Mandala (Kathmandu Valley) and Newar people like none?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4.The profound Epistemology and Soteriology of Anuttara Trika Tantra otherwise known as Kashmir Shaivism has survived despite the radical Islamic crush on Kashmiri Pundits in Kashmir. In the last century, had there been no Swami Lakshman Joo, the last of the great masters of the lineage from Kashmir, perhaps we would have never heard of Kashmir Saivism. What Swami Lakshman Joo imparted was enough to stir for its recognition in the world over. In fact, the world renowned practitioner-scholars of Tantra like Alexis Sanderson and Mark Dyczkowski both are his student. However, the krama process and ritual liturgy that was needed for the practice of the many higher anuttara deities of Trika were somehow missing there. Discoveries of the texts of Kubjika Tantra in Nepal Mandal had surprised Sanderson and all other students of Lakshman Joo (even Joo himself visited twice to Kathmandu in 1988 and 1990). Joo&amp;rsquo;s student Mark Dyczkowski had started visiting Nepal Mandala in 80&amp;rsquo;s and though discovered many more tantra texts relevant to Kashmir Saivism he didn&amp;rsquo;t find the living tradition, so he thought this practice must have been now lost/dead in the whole of Indian subcontinent. But wait, in 1987 a young Rajopadhyaya Brahmin (Newah) named Kedar from Bhaktapur had the courage to say that he was initiated into such lineage. Mark was then astonished to discover a secret society of Tantrik Community within the Newah people. Just like the Tantrik Buddhism that was vanished in Indian-Subcontinent was survived by Newah Bajracharyas and Shakyas, so was here the secret Kaula Tantric Practices of Shaiva Dharma that was dead in Indian-subcontinent was preserved by Newah Rajopadhyayas and Karmacharyas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>राजारामजशङ्कर-प्रस्तुतिः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/articles/rAjArAmaja-shankara-prastutiH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/articles/rAjArAmaja-shankara-prastutiH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Consciousness is all pervading. It is inherently self aware (=vimarśa), otherwise it would be no better than a lamp.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the ideal realm, there are generalized objects, generalized space and generalized time. Consciousness projects these outside, giving rise to specific objects in specific space and time.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Poets are somehow able to access these generalized objects.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
