<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;0 on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/0/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;0 on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Note on Alexis Sanderson and Indology</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/0/A_Note_on_Alexis_Sanderson_and_Indology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/0/A_Note_on_Alexis_Sanderson_and_Indology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dominic Goodall and Harunaga Isaacson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the occasion of the Symposium organised by Srilata Raman and Shaman Hatley in Toronto in March 2015, Harunaga Isaacson was given the gratifying but also daunting task of delivering a eulogy of Alexis Sanderson. This note is only very slightly based on what we, Dominic Goodall and Harunaga Isaacson, remember of the speech given on the occasion, since it was in large part extem porised from skeletal notes, and since it contained jokes and science-fictional scenarios that worked well in the telling, but that proved hard to commit to writing without losing their intended flavour.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contents</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/0/Contents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/0/Contents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Preface xi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;List of Figures and Tables xii&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notes on Contributors xiv&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Note on Alexis Sanderson and Indology xxv&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dominic Goodall and Harunaga Isaacson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bibliography of the Published Works of Alexis G.J.S. Sanderson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1983–2019) xxxi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dominic Goodall, Shaman Hatley, Harunaga Isaacson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and Srilata Raman&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Part 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early Śaivism&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 From Mantramārga Back to Atimārga: Atimārga as a Self-referential Term 15&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Peter C. Bisschop&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Why Are the Skull-Bearers (Kāpālikas) Called Soma? 33&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/0/Introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/0/Introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dominic Goodall, Shaman Hatley, Harunaga Isaacson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and Srilata Raman&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Academic study of Asia’s tantric traditions has blossomed in recent decades. Once dismissed as marginal, or unworthy of serious attention, we now under stand the Śaiva, Buddhist, Vaiṣṇava, and Jaina tantric traditions as integral to the religious and cultural landscapes of medieval South, Southeast, Central, and East Asia. This shift, which is reshaping the historiography of medieval India, is in no small measure due to the magisterial contributions of Alexis G.J.S. Sanderson, Fellow of All Souls College and Spalding Professor of Eastern Religion and Ethics at Oxford University, from 1992–2015, and now Emeritus Fellow of All Souls College. The present book is a collection of essays in his hon our, written by specialists of the various fields he has influenced from around the world, most of whom were his students at Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List of Figures and Tables</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/0/List_of_Figures_and_Tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/0/List_of_Figures_and_Tables/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;figures&#34;&gt;Figures&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4.1 Self as essence 88&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4.2 Self as substance 88&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4.3 Self as agent 89&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4.4 Rāmakaṇṭha’s view in the middle ground 91&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4.5 Rāmakaṇṭha’s view as equivalent to Nyāya 94&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4.6 Rāmakaṇṭha’s view as more extreme than Nyāya 96&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4.7 Nyāya as equivalent to Rāmakaṇṭha’s view 99&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5.1 Manuscript S3 of Abhinavagupta’s Īśvarapratyabhijñāvimarśinī (f. 43A), with fragments 4 and 5 of Utpaladeva’s Vivṛti on vv. 1.5.8–9 in the top and right margins (photograph: National Archives of India). 108&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Contributors</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/0/Notes_on_Contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/0/Notes_on_Contributors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Diwakar Acharya&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;is the Spalding Professor of Eastern Religions and Ethics at Oxford University, a fellow of All Souls College. Before succeeding Professor Sanderson at Oxford, he was a visiting lecturer and then associate professor of Indological Studies at Kyoto University (2006–2016), before which he held positions at Hamburg Uni versity and Nepal Sanskrit University. His research covers a wide range of topics in Indian religious and philosophical traditions, Upaniṣadic studies, epigraphy, the early history of Nepal, ritual, and Sanskrit literature. Recent publications include Early Tantric Vaiṣṇavism. Three Newly Discovered works of the Pañcar ātra: The Svāyambhuvapañcarātra, Devāmṛtapañcarātra and Aṣṭādaśavidhāna (Pondicherry, 2015), and a number of articles, such as“ ‘This world, in the begin ning, was phenomenally non-existent’: Āruṇi’s Discourse on Cosmogony in the Chāndogya Upaniṣad” ( Journal of Indian Philosophy 44.5, 2016). Acharya now also serves as editor-in-chief of the Journal of Indian Philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preface</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/0/Preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/0/Preface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This volume results from a symposium held at the University of Toronto in honour of Alexis G.J.S. Sanderson. The symposium was convened in March 2015 in anticipation of his retirement as the Spalding Professor of Eastern Reli gions and Ethics at All Souls College, Oxford University. The event was con ceived by Srilata Raman, who worked tirelessly and resourcefully to make it a success. In this she was aided by Shaman Hatley, co-convener of the sym posium, and a number of graduate students, especially Kalpesh Bhatt, Tamara Cohen, Larissa Fardelos, Nika Kuchuk, and Eric Steinschneider, to whom we offer our sincere thanks. It was immensely satisfying to have so many of Pro fessor Sanderson’s former doctoral students assemble from across the world for the occasion, students whose graduate studies at Oxford spanned more than three decades of Alexis Sanderson’s teaching career. The volume is based mainly on papers presented in the symposium, with additional contributions by several of his former pupils who had not been able to present their work at that time (Parul Dave-Mukherji, Csaba Dezső, Csaba Kiss, Ryugen Tanemura, and Anthony Tribe), as well as by Diwakar Acharya, his successor to the Spald ing Professorship. We would also like to extend our thanks and recognition to those who enriched the symposium with excellent papers, but who for various reasons could not include these in the present volume: Hans Bakker, Gudrun Bühnemann, Shingo Einoo, Alexander von Rospatt, and Somadeva Vasudeva.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
