<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Davis on ritual on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Davis on ritual on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>0</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Illustrations vii  Preface ix  Acknowledgments xiii  Abbreviations xv&lt;br&gt;&#xA;INTRODUCTION&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Locating the Tradition 3&lt;br&gt;&#xA;CHAPTER ONE&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Ritual and Human Powers 22&lt;br&gt;&#xA;CHAPTER TWO&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Oscillation in the Ritual Universe 42&lt;br&gt;&#xA;CHAPTER THREE&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Becoming a Siva 83&lt;br&gt;&#xA;CHAPTER FOUR&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Summoning the Lord 112&lt;br&gt;&#xA;CHAPTER FIVE&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Relations of Worship 137  CONCLUSION 163&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Notes 165  Glossary 181  Selected Bibliography 189  Index 195&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;illustrations&#34;&gt;Illustrations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;figures&#34;&gt;FIGURES&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Emission and reabsorption of the tattvas 43  2. Imposition of mantras onto the hand 49  3. Locations of domains 54  4. Subtle anatomy and domains 56  5. Diagrams for establishing pots 65  6. Siva&amp;rsquo;s entourages 67  7. Transfer of five kalas to the pasasutra 97  8. Siva&amp;rsquo;s supports 122  9. Divine throne and divine body 127&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Locations of the twelve kalas 130  11. ThemeetingofworshiperandSiva 135&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;plates&#34;&gt;PLATES&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;{following page 74)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Ritual and Human Powers</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/1_Ritual_and_Human_Powers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/1_Ritual_and_Human_Powers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ŚAIVA RITUAL is grounded in and grows out of the world that is known  metaphysically through Śaiva siddhanta philosophy. It is within this world  that the worshiper acts ritually. Accordingly, we must begin our reenact ment of puja by comprehending in a preliminary manner how that world is  fashioned: its fundamental constituents, the situation of human beings  within it, the most important goals of human endeavor, and how purposeful  action such as ritual may enable one to gain these goals. This preliminary  description delineates a Śaiva &amp;ldquo;theory&amp;rdquo; of ritual, or, to put it more accu rately, a matrix of propositions that constitute the world within which  Śaivas conceptualize and practice ritual.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Oscillation in the Ritual Universe</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/2_Oscillation_in_the_Ritual_Universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/2_Oscillation_in_the_Ritual_Universe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE UNIVERSE oscillates. It comes and goes, emerges and disappears. This  is a basic cosmological tenet for many schools of Hindu thought: the uni verse as we know it undergoes an endless cycle of creations and destruc tions. Within each cycle, the cosmos begins as an undifferentiated &amp;ldquo;some thing&amp;rdquo; from which evolves, in orderly sequence, the multiplicity of creation  that we see all around us. In time the cosmos exhausts itself, and all this  multiplicity merges once again into its undifferentiated source. A period of  cessation or sleep follows, and then the cosmos begins its evolution again in  the next cycle. In this way, our universe oscillates between moments of  creation and destruction, evolution and involution, activity and quietude,  expansion and contraction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Becoming a Siva</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/3_Becoming_a_Siva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/3_Becoming_a_Siva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE FUNDAMENTAL GOAL for the Saivite, as for adherents of many other  Hindu systems of thought, is to attain mok$a (&amp;ldquo;final liberation&amp;rdquo;), the highest  state of being that can be achieved by the human soul. For Śaiva philoso phy, the central drama of the cosmos is that of the human soul, immersed in  a state of bondage, moving gradually toward moksa through diva&amp;rsquo;s grace.  All else revolves around this. The entire oscillating universe, say the texts,  is emitted and reabsorbed just to facilitate the soul&amp;rsquo;s progress toward libera tion. All of diva&amp;rsquo;s five fundamental activities are oriented to enabling the  soul to attain liberation. As Mrgendragama asserts, &amp;ldquo;the soul is the reason  for everything&amp;rdquo; (MrA vidya 6.7).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Summoning the Lord</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/4_Summoning_the_Lord/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/4_Summoning_the_Lord/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE LORD SIVA is not limited the way we humans are. Theological de scriptions of Siva emphasize that the many limitations we experience as  embodied human beings in a state of bondage do not in any way affect  Siva. Human beings are limited in time; Siva is eternal, without beginning,  middle, or end. Our human bodies are confined in space; Siva is pervasive,  omnipresent. As paSus, we are constrained by fetters; Siva is eternally with out mala, liberated without beginning. Humans are characteristically agi tated by psychic disturbances, alternately attracted and repulsed by the  things of the world; Siva is completely calm. We humans are always de pendent on and subordinate to other beings; Siva is the one completely  independent, autonomous being. Humans possess finite capacities; Siva&amp;rsquo;s  powers of knowledge and action are infinite. Ultimately, Siva is not  bounded even by our capacity to conceptualize him. Siva is the one &amp;ldquo;whose  domain surpasses our speech and mind.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Relations of Worship</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/5_Relations_of_Worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/5_Relations_of_Worship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;rsquo; T HE WORSHIP of Siva consists in delivering over to a Siva-Iinga or the like  purified substances according to one&amp;rsquo;s own volition, with faith, and accom panied by activities of mind, speech, and body, such as particularly medita tions, mantra recitations, and mudrds, and accompanied also by the various  auxiliaries of worship preceding and following it&amp;quot; (§SPbh p. 37). As in  many Hindu schools of ritual, the Smva author Suryabhana defines piija by  its core action: the &amp;ldquo;delivering over&amp;rdquo; (samarpana) or &amp;ldquo;presentation&amp;rdquo; (dana)  of substances to the god. He regards other ritual actions such as self-purifi cation and invocation, which have occupied our attention in previous chap ters, as &amp;ldquo;auxiliaries&amp;rdquo; that establish the setting in which the transactions be tween human and god may take place. The central and irreducible act of  worship occurs only when the worshiper presents his &amp;ldquo;services&amp;rdquo; (upacara)  or tokens of homage to Siva.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/6_CONCLUSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/6_CONCLUSION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IN THE FINAL SECTION of the Sivapurana, after the wind-god Vayu has given  the eager sages of the Naimisa forest preliminary instruction in the siva jnana, he concludes his discourse with a statement about the character of  knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is said to be of two types, indirect (paroksa, literally &amp;ldquo;beyond one&amp;rsquo;s  own sight&amp;rdquo;) and direct. Indirect knowledge is unstable, they say, while direct  knowledge is very firm. Knowledge acquired through reasoning and instruction  is considered indirect knowledge; direct knowledge will arise through the most  excellent practice of ritual. Deciding that you cannot obtain moksa without direct  knowledge, you should exert yourselves assiduously to master this excellent  practice. ($Pur Vdyaviya 1.31.98-100)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/Glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/Glossary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;abhiseka — Anointment, rite by which lordly powers are affused onto a re cipient.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;acamana — &amp;ldquo;Sipping-water,&amp;rdquo; one of the upac ras offered to a guest or to  a divinity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;acarya — Śaiva priest, qualified to perform puja on behalf of others.  c ryabhiseka — &amp;ldquo;Priestly anointment&amp;rdquo; conferring status of acarya on Śaiva  initiate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adharasakti — The &amp;ldquo;Supporting Sakti&amp;rdquo; at the base of the divy sana.  adhik ra — Appointment or assignment to perform a role or function.  adhik rin — Agent employed by a superior to carry out some assignment.  disaiva — &amp;ldquo;Original Śaiva,&amp;rdquo; Śaiva br hmana.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/Notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/Notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LOCATING THE TRADITION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The scholarly literature on puja is not large, considering its importance within  Hindu traditions. For descriptions of puja in various schools, see James Burgess,  &amp;ldquo;The Ritual of Ramesvaram,&amp;rdquo; Indian Antiquary 12 (1883): 313-26; T. Goudriaan,  &amp;ldquo;Vaikhanasa Daily Worship according to the handbooks of Atri, Bhrgu, Kasyapa,  and Marici,&amp;rdquo; Indo-Iranian Journal 12 (1970): 161-215; R. V. Joshi, Le ritual de la  devotion Krsnaite (Pondich6ry: Institut Fransais d&amp;rsquo;Indologie, 1959); K. Ranga chari, The Sii Vaisnava Brahmans (Madras: Government Press, 1931); and Mrs.  Sinclair Stevenson, The Rites of the Twice-Born (London: Oxford University Press,  1920), pp. 368-400. The most useful translations of puja texts are those of Ηέΐέηβ  Brunner-Lachaux, Somaiambhupaddhati, premiere partie (Pondichdry: Institut  Franiais d&amp;rsquo;Indologie, 1963), and T. Goudriaan, Kasyapa&amp;rsquo;s Book of Wisdom (The  Hague: Mouton, 1965). Two notable ethnographic accounts are Paul B. Courtright,  &amp;ldquo;On This Holy Day in My Humble Way: Aspects of Puja,&amp;rdquo; in J. P. Waghome and  N. Cutler (eds.), Gods of Flesh/Gods of Stone (Chambersburg, Pa.: Anima Publica tions, 1985), pp. 33-50; and Akos Ostor, The Play of the Gods (Chicago: Univer sity of Chicago Press, 1980).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selected Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/Selected_Bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/Selected_Bibliography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;sanskrit-sources-by-title&#34;&gt;SANSKRIT SOURCES BY TITLE&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Texts and Translations)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agnipumna. Edited by Hari Narayana Apte. Anandasrama Sanskrit Series, no. 41.  Translated by Manmatha Nath Dutt. 3 vols. Calcutta: Elysium Press, 1903.  . Translated by N. Gangadharan. 3 vols. Ancient Indian Tradition and  Mythology Series, nos. 27-29. Delhi: Motilal Banarsidass, 1984.  Ajitagama. Edited by N. R. Bhatt. 2 vols. Pondich6ry: Institut Fran^ais d&amp;rsquo;lndolo gie, 1964,1967.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Affaprakarana. Includes TattvaprakdSa, Tattvasarpgraha, Tattvatrayanirnaya, Rat natraya, Bhogakarika, NadaMrika, Mok$akarika, and Paramokfanirasakarika.  Edited by N. Krishna Sastri. 2 vols. Devakottai: Śaivagamasiddhantaparipala nasangha, 1923, 1925.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Word Index</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/word-Index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/davis_on_ritual/word-Index/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;abandonment (ty ga), 159-60&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;abhi$eka. See anointment&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;acarya. See priest&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;action, ritual (kriy ), 31-32; and karman,  86-87; and knowledge, ix, xii, 32, 34- 35, 73-74, 163-64; as power of con sciousness, 23, 25, 84, 113,133-34, 162  activities, diva&amp;rsquo;s five fundamental&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;116; visualization of, 67-68. See also  mantras&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;anointment (abhifeka): of kings, 99,149; of  , linga, 64-67, 149; of priests and adepts,  36, 40, 70,100n.14,149&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;antyesti (cremation), 36, 109-10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;anugr ha. See grace&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
