<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;स्थानेश्वरः on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/sthAneshvaraH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;स्थानेश्वरः on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/sthAneshvaraH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>bhUta-shuddhiH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/sthAneshvaraH/bhUta-shuddhiH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/sthAneshvaraH/bhUta-shuddhiH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;स्रोतः - नेपाल-सर्वाम्नाय-तन्त्र-दीक्षित-स्थानेश्वरार्य-चित्रम् भूतशुद्धिम् अधिकृत्य किञ्चन।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bhūtaśuddhi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meditate deeply on the earth element and its bīja LAṀ as located in the base of the spine. Feel its solidity and firmness permeating your entire body. Meditate on it as the smell-principle. See it getting dissolved within the LAṀ bīja.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meditate deeply on the water element and its bīja VAṀ as located in the pubic area. Feel its fluidity and cohesion permeating your entire body. Meditate on it as the taste-principle. See it getting dissolved within the VAṀ bīja.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meditate deeply on the fire element and its bīja RAṀ as located in the navel area. Feel its warmth, heat and luminosity permeating your entire body. Meditate on it as the visual-principle. See it getting dissolved within the RAṀ bīja.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meditate deeply on the air element and its bīja YAṀ as located in the chest. Feel its movement and vitality permeating your entire body. Meditate on it as the touch-principle. See it getting dissolved within the YAṀ bīja.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meditate deeply on the space element and its bīja HAṀ as located in the throat. Feel its openness and clarity permeating your entire body. Meditate on it as the sound-principle. See it getting dissolved in the HAṀ bīja.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meditate deeply on the mind and its bīja OṀ as located in the point between the eyebrows.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OMkAraH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/sthAneshvaraH/OMkAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/sthAneshvaraH/OMkAraH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OṀ Uccāra&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recite A-U-Ṁ for as long as you can, placing the “A” around the navel area, the “U” around the chest area, and the “Ṁ” from the palate, up through the center of the eyebrows, all the way up to the crown of the head and above. Feel the spontaneous mūlabandha pressure and listen to the subtle resonance of the sound as it travels up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vimarsha-initiation-notes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/sthAneshvaraH/vimarsha-initiation-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/sthAneshvaraH/vimarsha-initiation-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vimarshafoundation.org/challenge-page/introtosarvamnaya&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sarvāmnāya, the “All-Transmissions” school, is a Krama tradition of Śaiva-Śākta Tantra that integrates all of the diverse streams of Āgamic revelation - deity forms, contemplative disciplines, and philosophies - into a single coherent and synthetic system of sequential initiation (krama). Sarvāmnāya does not constitute a formal organization. Instead it is a tradition of practice and approach to philosophy that has been handed down from teacher to student beginning in the XIIth Century but containing elements of much greater antiquity, some believed by modern scholars to be extinct, which have historically been kept alive in Nepal up to the present day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
