<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Dyczkowski on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/Dyczkowski/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Dyczkowski on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/Dyczkowski/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dyczkowski Horvatic interview</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/Dyczkowski/Dyczkowski_Hortavik_interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/Dyczkowski/Dyczkowski_Hortavik_interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Editor’s Note:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Mark Dyczkowski is one of the world’s foremost scholars on Tantra and Kashmiri Trika Shaivism and has lived and worked in India for close to forty years. Both a scholar and a practitioner, he was initiated by the great Indian teacher Swami Laksmanjoo in the year 1976. He has an undergraduate degree from Banaras Hindu University and a Ph.D. from Oxford University, where he researched Kashmir Shaivism under the guidance of Professor Alexis Sanderson. Mark has published extensively including the 12 volume Manthanabhairava Tantra and is considered to be one of the world’s leading authorities on Tantric Shaivism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mark Dyczkowski self intro</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/Dyczkowski/Mark_Dyczkowski_self_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/Dyczkowski/Mark_Dyczkowski_self_intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Brief Autobiography of Mark Dyczkowski&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Screen Shot 2014-03-05 at 7.58.53 PM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I grew up in London where I was born in 1951. My mother was Italian and father Polish. The sixties was an intense experience for me as it was for countless other young people in the West. This was a time of tremendous creativity and reflection which brought about great and lasting changes in western society and culture. One of the major features of these developments was a strengthened contact with the East in which I too participated. India and Tibet, their culture and wisdom, enthralled me from my very first encounter with them. I read and dreamt of them. Indian music stirred the depth of my soul and flooded me with profound emotions. Like many others I read Vivekananda, Yogananda, the life of Ramakrishna, the Bhagavadgītā, the Tibetan Book of the Dead, Tibetan Yoga and Secret Doctrines, the Lankāvatārasūtra and more. I began learning sitar when I was 14 and a day has hardly passed since without it being in my hands. Exciting as it all was, the pace of life was very intense which, inevitably, took its toll on my young mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
