<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/pAshupataH/meta/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/pAshupataH/meta/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Vyomavyāpin in the</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/pAshupataH/meta/MT/2023-01-03_the-vyomavyapin-in-the-pasupata-tantra-and-a-discu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/pAshupataH/meta/MT/2023-01-03_the-vyomavyapin-in-the-pasupata-tantra-and-a-discu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2023/01/03/the-vyomavyapin-in-the-pasupata-tantra-and-a-discursion-on-nine-fold-rudra-mantra-s/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Vyomavyāpin in the Pāśupata-tantra and a discursion on nine-fold Rudra-mantra-s&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Pāśupata-tantra is a poorly understood śaiva text that is believed to be affiliated with the Pāśupata tradition of Lakulīśa. While the colophons of some manuscripts present it as “Lakulīśa-pravartita-Pāśupata-tantram”, internally, it presents itself as a teaching of Nandin to the Bhārgava sage Dadhīci upon direction by Rudra himself. While we have seen a text going by this name in certain manuscript catalogs and seen fragmentary manuscripts of it, only recently was a nearly complete version of the text partially edited. This is not the place to go into a detailed discussion of the affinities and the provenance of the text, but we will make the below observations:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pAshupata-tantra-vyomavyApI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/pAshupataH/meta/MT/pAshupata-tantra-vyomavyApI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/pAshupataH/meta/MT/pAshupata-tantra-vyomavyApI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1609315672093237248.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pAshupata-tantra is notable in providing a full uddhAra of the famed vyomavyApin mantra. It is mostly thought to be a unique mantra of the saiddhāntika-s. One could argue that the pAshupata-tantra being a late expression of the pAshupata-s borrowed this mantra from the saiddhAntika-s. However, we believe it emerged among the later pAshupata-s (i.e., subsequent to their Vedic representatives) but prior to the branching off of the streams of the mantra-mArga like the saiddhAntika-s. Our main reasons for holding this view are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The shaivas: the pAshupata-s</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/pAshupataH/meta/MT/2006-05-10_the-shaivas-the-pashupata-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/pAshupataH/meta/MT/2006-05-10_the-shaivas-the-pashupata-s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;लेखकः - &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;मनसतरङ्गिणीकारः&lt;/a&gt;।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The early evolution of the shaiva fold is a topic of tremendous interest&#xA;(I am only grazing the surface with regards to a few points here. One&#xA;may see some other notes on this topic elsewhere on this site). We&#xA;obviously have no strong traces of its para-vedic elements. But there&#xA;are several texts that pertain to the branching point of shaiva from&#xA;within the old vedic tradition. These texts include chiefly the rudra&#xA;pa~nchavaktra mantra-s and the shvetAshvatara of the kR^iShNa&#xA;yajurvedic tradition and the atharvashiras and the nIlarudra of the&#xA;atharvavedic tradition. Many principal elements of the shvetAshvatara&#xA;and the nIlarudra derive from the vedic rudra sUktaM-s seen in the R^ig,&#xA;yajur and atharvan saMhitAs. In the mahAbhArata we already have sections&#xA;that are clearly of a generalized shaiva origin and express their clear&#xA;connection to the vedic tradition including the importance of the&#xA;shatarudriya hymns borrowed from the classical vedic ritual tradition.&#xA;In addition, they provide an important hymn resembling the shatarudriya&#xA;in many ways, which is the ajAnana virachita rudra stuti. The paurANic,&#xA;classical and inscriptional evidence one can discern that the shaiva&#xA;fold had already differentiated into multiple distinct streams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
