<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;00 on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;00 on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About the Translator</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/About_the_Translator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/About_the_Translator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pandit Hemendra Nath Chakravarty was born in 1918 in the village of Kalihati, in the district of Mymensingh (now in Bangladesh), the son of Taraka Nath Chakravarty, an Ayurvedic physician. His family was initiated in the Kaulika tradition and worshiped Daksinā Kālī. He matriculated at the village high school in 1935, and studied Sanskrit and later Sāmkhya at the Balānanda Brahmacharyasram in Deoghar (Bihar). In 1939 he went to Varanasi and studied Nyāya under Pt. Vibhuti Bibhushana Bhattacharya, graduating in 1944 (Nyāya Tīrtha) and 1945 (Tarka Tīrtha) from Calcutta Government Sanskrit Association, and earn ing a B.Ed. in 1950. In 1958 he met the famous pandit Mahama hopadhyaya Gopinath Kaviraj and began to study with him. He remained closely associated with Kaviraj until the latter&amp;rsquo;s death in 1976. He edited the sayings of Ānandamayi Ma with the commentary by G. Kaviraj in Bengali. From 1987 to 1995 he was Chief Pandit in the Kalātattvakosa project of Indira Gandhi National Centre for the Arts, Varanasi Branch, which at that time was directed by Dr. Bettina Bāumer. He wrote articles for Kalātatt vakosa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contents</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Contents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Contents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Preface by Swami Chetanānanda Foreword by Boris Marjanovic Introduction by H.N. Chakravarty Abhinavagupta&amp;rsquo;s Tantrasāra&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chapter One Chapter Two Chapter Three Chapter Four Chapter Five Chapter Six Chapter Seven Chapter Eight Chapter Nine Chapter Ten Chapter Eleven Chapter Twelve Chapter Thirteen Chapter Fourteen Chapter Fifteen Chapter Sixteen Chapter Seventeen Chapter Eighteen Chapter Nineteen Chapter Twenty Chapter Twenty-One Chapter Twenty-Two Notes Bibliography: About the Translator&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foreword</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Foreword/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Foreword/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tantrasāra (TS), as its name suggests, is the summary of impor tant notions, principles, doctrines, and practices found in the Tantras in general and in the Tantrāloka (TA) in particular. The TĀ is Abhinavagupta&amp;rsquo;s most extensive work on the principles of nondual Śaiva doctrines written in verse, while the TS, which is its summary, is significantly shorter and written in prose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was the tradition of some of the ancient pandits belonging to different schools of Indian thought to write brief and simplified versions of the main principles and doctrines of their schools.+++(4)+++ The purpose of this practice was to provide those interested in the subject but unable to devote years of study to Sanskrit grammar and logic, deemed prerequisites for the study of any other branch of learning, with a simplified and comprehensible overview of the main principles of their respective schools. Abhinavagupta and his disciple Kșemarāja wholeheartedly embraced this practice. As early as the second benedictory verse of the TS, Abhinavagupta declares the complexity, vastness, and depth of the topics discussed in the TĀ as the main reason for writing its short version.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tantrasāra of Abhinavagupta&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Translated from Sanskrit with Introduction and Notes by H.N. Chakravarty&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Edited by Boris Marjanovic&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Preface by Swami Chetanānanda&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Abhinavagupta, Rajanaka.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;स्रोतो &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/TantrasaraOfAbhinavaguptaH.N.Chakravarti/page/53/mode/2up&#34;&gt;ऽत्र&lt;/a&gt; ।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kashmir Saivism-Early works to 1800. 2. Tantrism-Early works to 1800. 3. Abhinayagupta, Rajanaka. Tantrāloka. I. Chakravarty, H.N., 1918-2011, translator, writer of added commentary. II. Marjanovic, Boris, editor. III. Abhinavagupta,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preface</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Preface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One day in May of 1980 in South Fallsburg, I was sitting in my room in between programs at the Siddha Yoga Ashram reading some science fiction book, when Muktānanda came in the room. As always, when Swami Muktānanda came in the room, every body&amp;rsquo;s foreheads immediately hit the floor, and that day was no exception.+++(5)+++ Mine was on the floor immediately. The first thing Muktānanda did in looking around the room while I was on the floor was to note there was a book on the bed. He asked me what it was. I told him, and he said, “Don&amp;rsquo;t read that; read Kashmir Saivism.&amp;quot; And that began my decades-long interest in the study of what is now called Sakta-Saivism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
