<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;rastogi-navajIvana-intro on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/meta/articles/rastogi-navajIvana-intro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;rastogi-navajIvana-intro on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/meta/articles/rastogi-navajIvana-intro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 EXPLORING THE TANTRALOKA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/meta/articles/rastogi-navajIvana-intro/1_EXPLORING_THE_TANTRALOKA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/meta/articles/rastogi-navajIvana-intro/1_EXPLORING_THE_TANTRALOKA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Strange as it may appear, the Tantrāloka happens to be the only major &amp;lsquo;original&amp;rsquo; work of Abhinava while his all other important works&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; come to us in the form of a commentary on some earlier valuable text notwithstanding his own description of the Tantrāloka as a gloss, as we shall see in the sequel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-traditional-approach-to-the-tantrāloka&#34;&gt;1 Traditional Approach to the Tantrāloka&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A peep into and a look around the Tantrāloka off- ers many illuminating insights. Towards twelfth century Śivānanda, the author of the R̥juvimarśinī, refers to it as the Trika-śāstra&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; or Trika-saraśāstra&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and the verses cited are traceable to the published edition of the Tantrāloka. It, therefore, appears that by that time it came to be regarded as the most representative text of Trika system. Kṣemarāja, the illustrious pupil of Abhinavagupta, talks of two characteristics of the text. One, it was composed in the state of Absolutic trance&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 ABOUT THE AUTHOR ABHINAVAGUPTA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/meta/articles/rastogi-navajIvana-intro/2_ABOUT_THE_AUTHOR_ABHINAVAGUPTA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/meta/articles/rastogi-navajIvana-intro/2_ABOUT_THE_AUTHOR_ABHINAVAGUPTA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(i) Biographical data&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It will be appropriate if we begin with the biogra- phical data as made available by Abhinavagupta in the Tantraloka. Abhinavagupta gives graphic details of his ancestry, parentage, teachers, pupils and cir- cumstances under which the Tantraloka was written.1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) NAME&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to the Tantraloka Abhinavagupta was not his actual name. It was a title which he earned from his teachers in recognition of his devotion to and reflection upon Siva. This fact has already been emphasized earlier where, according to Jayaratha, his name implied authoritativeness. Abhinavagupta is never tired of repeating this fact. He calls himself competent. This leads to the natural conclusion that&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 ABOUT THE COMMENTATOR JAYARATHA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/meta/articles/rastogi-navajIvana-intro/3_ABOUT_THE_COMMENTATOR_JAYARATHA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/meta/articles/rastogi-navajIvana-intro/3_ABOUT_THE_COMMENTATOR_JAYARATHA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The illustrious author of the Viveka commentary, Jayaratha, is next to Abhinavagupta alone in impor- tance. He is no ordinary commentator. He reli- giously follows the methodology adopted by his mas- ter and creates a sort of complete independent text which not only expatiates upon the Tantrāloka but also supplements, complements and defends as it were. But for the Viveka we would never understand the Tantrāloka. An attempt will be made to evaluate and appreciate Jayaratha&amp;rsquo;s contribution in the pages that follow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 ABOUT THE TEXT</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/meta/articles/rastogi-navajIvana-intro/4_ABOUT_THE_TEXT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/meta/articles/rastogi-navajIvana-intro/4_ABOUT_THE_TEXT/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(I) KSTS Edition: editorial and printing lapses&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Tantraloka is a very voluminous work of Abhi- navagupta and togetherwith Jayaratha&amp;rsquo;s commen- tary covers twelve volumes in bold print brought out in the Kashmir Series of Texts and Studies spread over 3718 pages.1 The Tantraloka, as printed, com- prises roughly 6000 verses, 5844 1/2 to be exact. The fact that two verses, T.A. 37.4-5, have been re- peated as T.A. 37.10 1/2-12 1/2 does not reduce the number because this anomaly is a legacy from the time of Jayaratha himself having been retained in his script itself. The sum total of the printed verse- numbers at 5842, therefore, does not give the cor- rect picture because of several printing mistakes and editorial lapses resulting in occasional duplication and omission of numbers as well as treatment of half- verses as full ones. An effort has been made to as- semble all such cases in the chart given below to offer a tabular view.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 AGENDA FOR FUTURE RESEARCH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/meta/articles/rastogi-navajIvana-intro/5_AGENDA_FOR_FUTURE_RESEARCH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/meta/articles/rastogi-navajIvana-intro/5_AGENDA_FOR_FUTURE_RESEARCH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the very outset we pointed out the limitations of the present &amp;lsquo;Introduction&amp;rsquo;. It is at the most an elementary attempt to under- stand the technique of the Tantrāloka by piecing together obvious but scattered indications about its contents, their organic treat- ment and the guiding norms that characterised the approach of two master minds. An attempt has also been made to enlarge and deepen our familiarity with the environ, contributions, and personal details of the author and the commentator of the Tantra- loka. In Indian parlance it offers a Bahiranga treatment. It covers only two steps of the ladder-where to study and how to study, leaving the third-what to study-for future. Our conclusions are approximations in the present state of our knowledge. This &amp;ldquo;Introduction&amp;rsquo;, therefore, does not go beyond this point and is not intended to be a substitute for a &amp;lsquo;research work&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;study&amp;rsquo;. Its purpose will be amply realised if it arouses interest of the scho- larly world to undertake deeper and meaningful studies in future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
