<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;bhairava art religion on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;bhairava art religion on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>0 About</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/0_About/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/0_About/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A path breatking new approach to the study of Indian Art and religion, the work bases its analysis on the subject on two rare Sanskrit texts, &lt;em&gt;Sarva-siddhānt-viveka,&lt;/em&gt; (Critical understanding of all religious systems) and &lt;em&gt;Jñāna-siddhi&lt;/em&gt; (Achievement of Knowledge) through which the meaning and identitfication of some of the breadth taking sculptures of India like Elephanta Trimurti are discussed. After introducing the as many as thirty various Schools of Śaivism and “Śākta-Vāma tantras” the date and authorship of the Sanskrit texts are detailed both from North and South Indian perspective and their contents summarized.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>0 bibliography</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/0_bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/0_bibliography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;primary-sources&#34;&gt;Primary Sources&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Annual Reports on Epigraphy&lt;/em&gt;, Govt. of India.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aṣṭa Prakaraṇam&lt;/em&gt;, text with commentaries, Ed. Pandit Sri Vrajavallabha Dwivedi, Varanasi, 1988.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chidambara-kshetra-sarvasva&lt;/em&gt;, Ed. Rajamahendram, 1977.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Epigraphia Indica&lt;/em&gt; Volumes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Īśāna-gurudeva-Paddhati&lt;/em&gt; — 4 volumes, Ed. T. Ganapati Sastri, Bharatiya Vidya Prakashan, Delhi, First edition, 1920, 2nd edition — 1990.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Īśāna-gurudeva-Paddhati&lt;/em&gt;, Vol.V, Ganapati Sastri T., Bharatiya Vidya Prakashan, Delhi, Reprint, 1990&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jñānavaraṇa-Viḷakkam and Mahāpatiyam&lt;/em&gt; Pt. I Dharmapura Adhinam, 1957.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jñānavarana-Viḷakkam and Mahāpatiyam&lt;/em&gt; Pt. II. Dharmapura Adhinam, 1959.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kāmikāgama&lt;/em&gt;, (&lt;em&gt;Pūrvabhāaga&lt;/em&gt;), Ed. C. Swaminatha Sivacharya, South Indian Arccaka Association, Madras 1975.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kāmikāgama&lt;/em&gt;, (&lt;em&gt;Uttarabhāga&lt;/em&gt;) 1988&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kiraṇa-vṛtti&lt;/em&gt; with Bhatta Ramakanta&amp;rsquo;s commentary Vol. I, Chapters 1-6, corneal edition Dominic Goodall, IFP, Pondichery, 1998.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kulārnava Tantra text and Readings, woodroffe John Sir, and Pandit, Motilal Banarsidass, New Delhi, Reprint, 1984.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Liṅga-purāṇa&lt;/em&gt;, Ed. Jagadisa Sastri, motilal Banarsi das, Delhi,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Malini-vijayottara Tantram&lt;/em&gt;, (Kashmir series of texts and studies), Pandit Madhusudan Kaul Sastri, Bombay. 1922.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Manimekhalai&lt;/em&gt; (Tamil) Ed. Murray S. Rajam, Madras, 1957.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mattavilāsa prahasanam&lt;/em&gt; of Mahendra Pallava, Ed. Unni.N.P., Nag Publishers, Delhi, 1998&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meykaṇṭa-sāttiram&lt;/em&gt;, Dharmapura Adhinam, 1956.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mṛgendra Tantram&lt;/em&gt;, with Ramakanta&amp;rsquo;s commentary, Madhusudan Kaul Sastri, Mehar chand and Lakshman das, New Delhi, Reprint, 1982&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Para-trisikha-Vivaraṇa&lt;/em&gt; of Abhinava Gupta, Text Svami Lakshmnju, Translation by Jaidev singh Ed. By Bettina Baumer, Motilal Banassidass, New Delhi. 1988&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sadā-śiva-rūpam&lt;/em&gt; (Tamil), old commentary by Sirkāli Sattanatha vallal with Thiruvaduturai Adhinam, 1954.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Śaiva-paribhāṣā&lt;/em&gt; of Śivagrayogi, Text and Translation, S.S. Suryanarayana Sastri, Ed. R. Balasubrahmanian and V.K.S.N. Raghavan, University of Madras, 1982.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sarva-darśana-sangraha&lt;/em&gt;, of Madhavacharya, Asiatic society of Bengal, Calcutta, 1986.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Śiva-yoga-ratna&lt;/em&gt; of Jñāna Prakasa, Text, Translation, Note Tara Michael, IFIP., Pondichery, 1975.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;South Indian Inscriptions series&lt;/em&gt;, Government of India&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Svacchanda Tantram&lt;/em&gt; with the commentary of Kshemarāja, 5 volumes, Sampurnanand Sanskrit Visvavidyalaya, Varanasi, 1992.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Vināśika Tantra&lt;/em&gt;, Text, Translation, Tenn Gondriaan Motilal Banarsidass Delhi, 1985&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Viṣṇu-Dharmottara-Purāṇa&lt;/em&gt;, Ed Priya Bala Sha, Gaekward Oriental series, Vadodara, 1994&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;secondary-sources&#34;&gt;Secondary sources&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Adhir Chakravarti, &lt;em&gt;India and South East Asia: Socio Economic cultural contacts&lt;/em&gt; Punthi Pusthak, Calcutta, 1998.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Agrawala.V.S., &lt;em&gt;Indian Art&lt;/em&gt;, Prithvi Prakashan, Varanasi, 2003&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alexis Sanderson, &lt;em&gt;History through Textual Criticism, in the Study of Saivism, Pañcaratra and Buddhist Yogini tantras, Les sources de temples&lt;/em&gt;, Ed.Francois Grimmal, Institut Francais de Indology, Pondichery, 2001&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Banerjee.J.N., &lt;em&gt;The Development of Hindu Iconography&lt;/em&gt;, Munshiram Manohar Lal Publishers, New Delhi, 2002, Reprint&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Barua Benemadhatb, &lt;em&gt;A History of Pre Buddhist Indian Philosophy&lt;/em&gt; Reprint, Motilal Banarsidass, Delhi 1981.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bhandarkar, R.G., &lt;em&gt;Vaishniavism Saivism and minor religious systems&lt;/em&gt;. Reprint Asian Educational Services, New Delhi, 1983&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cowell E.B., and Gough A.E., &lt;em&gt;Sarva-Darśana-Sangraha&lt;/em&gt; of Madhavacharya, Text and Translation, Parimal Publications, Delhi, 1986.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Charles Dallard Collins, &lt;em&gt;The Inconography and ritual of Śiva at Elephanta&lt;/em&gt;, Sadguru publications, Delhi, 1991&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Devangana Desai, &lt;em&gt;The Religious imagery of Khajuraho&lt;/em&gt;, Project for Indian Cultural Studies, Mumbai, 1996&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gerd Kresel, &lt;em&gt;Die Śiva Bilwarke der Mathura Kunst&lt;/em&gt;, Franz Steiner, Verlag, Wiesbaten, GMBH, Stutgart, 1986.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gopinath Kaviraj, &lt;em&gt;Notes on Religion and Philosophy&lt;/em&gt;, Sampurnan Sanskrit University, Varanasi, 1987.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;In The Image of Man&lt;/em&gt;, Published by Art Council of Great Britain, London, 1982&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jitendranath Banerjee, the &lt;em&gt;Development of Hindu Iconography&lt;/em&gt;, by, Munshiram Manoharlal Publishers, New Delhi, 2002.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Karl J Khandavala, &lt;em&gt;Indian Bronze Master pieces&lt;/em&gt;, Festival of India, N. Delhi, 1988&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Krishnadēva, &lt;em&gt;Temples of India&lt;/em&gt;, Aryan Books International, New Delhi, 1995, 2 Vol&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lorenzen, David N., &lt;em&gt;The Kāpālikās and Kālāmukhas&lt;/em&gt;, Two lost Saivite sects, Thomson Press, New Delhi, 1972.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Malini-vijayottaratantra&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Pandit Madhusudan Kanl Sastri, Kashmir Samskrita grantavali, Srinagar - Kashmir, 1922.6 na&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maxwell. T.S., &lt;em&gt;Viśva-rūpa&lt;/em&gt;, Oxford Univesrity Press, Delhi, 1988.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maxwell.T.S. &lt;em&gt;The Gods of Asia, Image, Text, and meaning&lt;/em&gt;, Oxford University, Press, Delhi, 1997.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mishra. O.P., &lt;em&gt;Mother Goddess in Central India&lt;/em&gt;, Agam Kala Prakashan, New Delhi, 1985.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mishra. R.N., &lt;em&gt;Sculptures from Dahala and Dakshina Kosala&lt;/em&gt;, Agam Kala Prkashan, Delhi 1987.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Michael W.Meister, ed. &lt;em&gt;Discourses on Śiva&lt;/em&gt;, Proceedings of of a symposium on the nature of Religious imagery, Vakil, Feiffer, and Simons Ltd, Bombay, 1984.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mṛgendra Tantram&lt;/em&gt;, with Ramakanta&amp;rsquo;s commentary, Madhusudan Kaul Sastri, Mehar chand and Lakshman das, New Delhi, Reprint, 1982.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nagaswamy.R., &lt;em&gt;Eastern Indian Contact with Tamilnadu&lt;/em&gt;, Journal of Bengal Art, No 3 Dhakka, 1998.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nagaswamy. R, “&lt;em&gt;Foundations of Indian Art., Ardhanari, Harihara and Natarāja&lt;/em&gt;”, in Foundations of Indian Art and Religion, Tamil Arts Academy, Chennai, 2003.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nallaswami Pillai, J.M., &lt;em&gt;Studies in Śaiva Siddhanta&lt;/em&gt;, Pt. I, Dharmapura Adhinam, 1962.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nandimath, S.C., &lt;em&gt;A Hand Book of Vīraśaivism&lt;/em&gt;, Motilal Banarsidass, Delhi, Reprint, 1979.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pratapaditya Pal, &lt;em&gt;Bronzes from Kashmir&lt;/em&gt;, Munishram Manoharlal, New Delhi, 1975&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pratabaditya Pal, &lt;em&gt;The Sensuous and immortals&lt;/em&gt;, A selection of Scultpures from the Pan Asian Collection, Los Angeles County Museum of Art, Californis, 1977.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pratapaditya Pal, &lt;em&gt;A Collecting Odyssy Indian, Himalayan, and South East Asian Art&lt;/em&gt;, The Art Institute of Chicago, Thames and Hudson, London, 1997.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pratapaditya Pal, &lt;em&gt;Art from the Indian Sub-contient&lt;/em&gt;, Norton Simon Art Foundation, 2003.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pratapaditya Pal, &lt;em&gt;Himalayas an Aesthetic experience&lt;/em&gt;, Art Institute of Chicago, 2004.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shantilal.Nagar, &lt;em&gt;Mahishasuramardini in Indian Art&lt;/em&gt;, Agam Kala Prakashan, New Delhi, 1982.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stella Kramrisch, &lt;em&gt;The Presence of Śiva&lt;/em&gt;, Princeton university Press, 1981.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sivaramamwiti. C., &lt;em&gt;Nataraja in Art, Thought, and Literature&lt;/em&gt;, National Museum, New Delhi, 1974.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stella Kramrisch, &lt;em&gt;The Hindu Temple 2 Volumes&lt;/em&gt;, Motilal Banarsi dass, Delhi, Reprint, 1986.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Trivedi, R.D., &lt;em&gt;Temples of the Pratihara Period, in Central India&lt;/em&gt;, Archaeological Survey of India, New Delhi, 1990.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tantraloka&lt;/em&gt;, of Abhinavagupta, with the commentary of Jayaratha, Vol. 1-8, ed. R.C. Dwivedi and Navajivan Rastogi, Motilal Banarsidass, Delhi, Reprint, 1987.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vasundhara Filliozat, (Mrs) Dr., &lt;em&gt;Kālāmukhas and Pāśupata temples in Dharwar&lt;/em&gt;, KSRI Chennai 4, 2001.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zimmer Heinrich, &lt;em&gt;Myths and Symbols in Indian Art and Civilization&lt;/em&gt;. Motilal Banarsidass, Delhi, Reprint, 1990.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>0 Preface</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/0_Preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/0_Preface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I dedicate this work with admiration and veneration to the greatest Śiva yogi, His Holiness, Śrīla Śrī. Shanmukha Deśika Jñānasambandha Paramāchārya Svāmikaḷ, the Mahāsannidhānam, who is the embodiment of &lt;em&gt;Śiva Carya&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Śiva Kriya&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Śiva Yoga&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Śiva Jñāna&lt;/em&gt;, and the 26th head of the Dharmapuram Adhīnam, Śaiva Mutt, Tamilnad, on his 81st birthday. I had the privilege of having his darśan and the benefit of his discourses on many occasion and found in him singular dedication to Śaiva worship and faith. His knowledge of Śaivism is unparalleled and he follows it as a way of life and not as an intellectual acquisition. He lives every minute in Śiva consciousness. His Holiness has absolute faith in Vedic, Āgamic and Purāṇic unity that is the foundation of Indian ethos and culture and strives to contribute to its proper understanding and appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1\ Sarva-Siddhānta-Vivēka and Jñāna-Siddhi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/1_Sarva-SiddhAnta-Viveka_and_JnAna-Siddhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/1_Sarva-SiddhAnta-Viveka_and_JnAna-Siddhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two Sanskrit texts, &lt;em&gt;Sarva-siddhānta Vivēka&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Jñāna-Siddhi&lt;/em&gt;, both of great importance to the study of history of Indian Śivaism are included in this volume. This work also gives a brief history about where these texts are found, the texts in original, followed by brief summaries of the contents of both texts and a crtical evaluation and their use to Śaiva art and religion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The text is found in a Tamil Commentary on &lt;em&gt;Jñāna-Āvarana-Viḷakkam&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by Veḷḷi-ambala-vāṇar Tambiran who was an extraordinary Śaiva exponent. According to tradition he was a contemporary of the celebrated Kumāra-guruparar who lived in the time of Tirumalai Nayak of Madurai who ruled in the middle of 17th cent. Veḷḷi-ambala-vāṇar belonged 17th cent. He is said to have gone to Vāranāsi to learn Śaiva systems, studied under Kumara-guruparar and has written an exhaustive commentary on the Tamil &lt;em&gt;Jñānāvaraṇa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; text. The interesting part of the text is he cites many important Sanskrit texts in a Tamil work. Veḷḷai-ambala-vāṇar cites more than 180 texts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2\ Sarva-Siddhānta-Vivēka</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/2_Sarva-SiddhAnta-Viveka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/2_Sarva-SiddhAnta-Viveka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The original text &lt;em&gt;Sarva-Siddhānta-Vivēka&lt;/em&gt; is not known to any other source apart from these citations in the commentary of &lt;em&gt;Jñānāvaraṇa-dīpikā&lt;/em&gt;. It is a very lucid commentary mainly meant to be useful to an ardent student of Śaiva system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The available text begins abruptly with &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Mantravada&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; also known as &lt;em&gt;Mantravāmi&lt;/em&gt;, and deals with nine sub-sects of Vāma schools of the Śāktas. However from the first sub sect described it is seen that the original should have contained several chapters preceding the present portion as it mentions, &amp;ldquo;as described earlier&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;prāk ukta vartmanā&lt;/em&gt;) in the very first verse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3\ Jñāna-Siddhi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/3_JnAna-Siddhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/3_JnAna-Siddhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jñānasiddhi&lt;/em&gt;, a text included in this volume is a rare work which may be called a lost āgama retrieved. Veḷḷi-ambala-vāṇar Śvamikaḷ has done a yeomen service by extensive citation from this text. From various references to this text in the commentary it is seen that it contained several chapters that have not been cited and what we have is only a part. According to Veḷḷi-ambala-vāṇar the &lt;em&gt;Jñānasiddhi&lt;/em&gt; is an Āgama, counted among 224 secondary Āgamas, the 28 sub Āgamas and the nine main Āgamas. It is listed along with the following Āgamas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 The Art of the Bhairavas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/4_The_Art_of_the_Bhairavas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/nAgasvAmI/bhairava-art-religion/4_The_Art_of_the_Bhairavas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A careful study of the history of Śaivism reveals that there were many sub-sects among the Śaivas that came into existence due to diverse approaches to the realization of the Supreme, though all accepted Śiva as the Supreme God. Time and space has contributed to these variations as well. Two broad divisions were accepted among these systems one following the calm and quiet path called Saumya School and the second the wild path called the Raudra School. Both were suited to individual taste and environment. Tamilnadu is mainly a flat country with not much wild forest or intractable regions. People live on cultivated lands that did not offer that much of terror or fear to the people as some other parts of India, which were infested with thick jungles, forests and hills in which people were living in constant fear and expectations of divine support to free them from enemies and natural disasters. The peaceful regional environment was conducive for Tamilnadu for seeking after higher knowledge, Jñāna throught the path of Jñāna-mārga Śaivism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
