<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Shaiva age end on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Shaiva age end on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01: Defamiliarizing the Brāhmaṇical World</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/01_Defamiliarizing_the_brAhmaNichal_Worl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/01_Defamiliarizing_the_brAhmaNichal_Worl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 1: Defamiliarizing the Brāhmaṇical World&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter engages with disparate and often difficult material culture and textual sources in the service of conveying some rather straightforward observations that I argue form the foundation of any philologically and historically responsible reading of particularized premodern Indic social realities as opposed to a narrow band of prescriptive doctrinal formulations. Most importantly, it seeks to demonstrate on empirical grounds some of the hermeneutical stumbling blocks that are posed by our easy embrace of conceptual frameworks like “Brāhmaṇism” and “Brāhmaṇical identity.” All too often, scholars of Hindu traditions treat these frameworks as if their content were self-evident, internally consistent, and cohesive—that is to say, as trans-historical categories—as opposed to ones that are historically and geographically contingent, internally contested, and constantly and often self-consciously evolving. Perhaps even more problematically, much of what has been called the sociological approach to the study of premodern Indian religion conflates the reconstruction of “social context” with the superimposition onto particularized archives of a delimited purportedly unchanging canon of “Brāhmaṇical normativity” centered upon a single interpretive perspective. To be quite blunt, as will become clear when you have reached the end of this chapter, such analysis consistently derives its precepts from one specific subset of Dharmaśāstra writings that are heavily inflected by the Pūrva Mīmāṃsaka exegetes. In essence, denuded of historicity, a single scholastic position is envisioned as representing the unchanging and virtually unchallenged heart of Brāhmaṇical tradition. The “sociological imagination” then proceeds to account for “historical change” as the series of self-perpetuating ideological contestations occurring within the binary of Brāhmaṇa/non-Brāhmaṇa conflict as&#xA;[[P129]]&#xA;they unfold within historical time. Indian history—its distant past as much as its present—thus becomes a narration of the irreconcilable clash between two ideologically static forces correlated with specific social forms—whether we call these Brāhmaṇa and Śramaṇa or Hindu and Subaltern—with “Brāhmaṇical normativity” almost always enacting the role of hegemon, a model that matches poorly with the fluid negotiations of meaning and identity so often evident in our documentary and textual records.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02: A Beginningless Transactionality</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/02_A_Beginningless_Transactionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/02_A_Beginningless_Transactionality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[[P307]]&#xA;Chapter 2: A Beginningless Transactionality: Recovering the Quotidian Institutional Realities of the Early Medieval&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-beginningless-transactionality&#34;&gt;A Beginningless Transactionality&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sampūrī was ten years old (&lt;em&gt;daśavarṣīyā saṃpūrīnāmnī&lt;/em&gt;) when first the soldiers and then the famine came, and her family was forced to flee their village.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In that trying time, her husband, her in-laws, even her own parents, were reduced to begging for their survival.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Seeking to spare the family one more mouth to feed, Sampūrī slipped away and set out on the road on her own.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; From village to village, door to door, at each home she begged for a single mouthful of food, but her hunger only grew. She could not fill her belly (&lt;em&gt;udarapuraṇāprāpti&lt;/em&gt;) and so her young [[P307]] body became severely emaciated (&lt;em&gt;atyantakṛśā&lt;/em&gt;). Her clothes become soiled, torn, and ragged (&lt;em&gt;malinagātrā jīrṇavastrakhaṇḍāvṛtā&lt;/em&gt;). She spent her nights in the half-way houses of monasteries, seeking shelter in temples and in the canopied structures along the roadside that housed great vessels filled with clean water for quenching the thirst of passing travelers (&lt;em&gt;devagṛha-maṭha-prapā- satrākārādisthāneṣu nivāsinī&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03: The King Must Protect the Difference</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/03_The_King_Must_Protect_the_Difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/03_The_King_Must_Protect_the_Difference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-3-the-king-must-protect-the-difference-the-juridical-foundations-of-tantric-knowledge&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: The King Must Protect the Difference: The Juridical Foundations of Tantric Knowledge&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;captured-in-stone-the-gurus-command-ājñā&#34;&gt;Captured in Stone: The Guru’s Command (Ājñā)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only surviving temple belonging to the &lt;em&gt;rājaguru&lt;/em&gt; of the Kalyāṇi Cāḷukya Emperor Vikramāditya VI (r. 1076–1126) CE lies tucked away out of sight on the far bank of a vast dried up lake, now little more than a sea of mud in which water buffaloes wallow.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Small, shorn of ornamentation, and fashioned in that unostentatious style favored by the Rāṣṭrakūṭas, it is difficult to distinguish from more modern concrete structures. Especially in contrast with the majestic landscape in which it is embedded, at first glance, Kūni Sōmēśvara is almost disappointingly ordinary. Only two features gesture towards the significant past of this deceptively simple place. On the one hand, there is a large boulder, framing a secluded grove found some paces to the right of the temple, on which one finds a two-foot-high engraving of a both a ghoul and a human devotee supplicating themselves before the awesome majesty of a standing Bhairava.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; On the other, embedded in the temple complex itself, there are two stone inscriptions (&lt;em&gt;śīlaśāsana&lt;/em&gt;), composed in a reasonably Sanskritic register of the old Kannada language, that serve as prelude to a fascinating and much neglected dimension of the religious life of the medieval Deccan.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04: Living in the Śaiva Age</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/04_Living_in_the_shaiva_Age/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/04_Living_in_the_shaiva_Age/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 4: Living in the Śaiva Age: Three Embodied Encounters with Authority and Responsibility&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;not-by-birth-but-by-the-sword-a-śūdra-big-man-makes-his-mark&#34;&gt;Not by Birth, but by the Sword: A Śūdra Big Man Makes His Mark&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Habbĕya Nāyaka was a singular hero (asahāyaśūra) who, by the power of his might, made decapitated corpses dance upon the battlefield.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; One day (ŏndu dĕvasam), this great warrior was reflecting to himself about the tales of other lone heroes of bygone days (purātanar) when he heard some &lt;em&gt;subhāṣitas&lt;/em&gt; being recited.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It is a matter of some serendipity that one of these Sanskrit verses has survived in stone down into the present day:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05: A Substantive Intervention</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/05_A_Substantive_Intervention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/05_A_Substantive_Intervention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 5: A Substantive Intervention: Reading the Material Culture of the Western Deccan Across Region and Dynasty&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More than one hundred miles from the Cāḷukya capital at Kalyana in the district of Bhoom, Osamanbad, lies a small village of scarcely ten thousand people. Despite its remoteness, it remains for certain caste communities an important site for pilgrimage, attracting devotees from as far away as Pune. Though in recent years the tradition has been emended to conform to the schedules of working people participating in a capitalist economy, it has long been customary that when a male child is born—on the sixth day he is alive—his parents would take him before Mother Sātwai, the goddess of the six.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06: Śākta Artisan Imaginaries</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/06_shAkta_Artisan_Imaginaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/06_shAkta_Artisan_Imaginaries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 6: Art and Terror in the City of Śiva: Śākta Artisan Imaginaries and the Making of a Material World&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-world-made-fit-for-images&#34;&gt;A World Made Fit for Images&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we have seen time and time again, as both social space and conceptual object, the Deccan was effectively defined by the translation—into text, praxis, and materiality—of very specific epistemological commitments that imagined the world as founded upon irreducible diversity. As this chapter will make clear, these acts of translation were very specifically the product of the life-world of the medieval artisans who quite literally built the Deccan, and about whom little of substance has been written. Our task in this chapter—through a sympathetic act of the imagination married to precise philological work—is to attend to the self-understanding of these social actors and to the institutional frameworks, especially matters of pedagogy and ritual professionalizations, that made them into the types of people seen as suited for carrying out their assigned social roles. In short, we will need to acclimate ourselves to what is entailed in being not the type of religious intellectual or functional authority who composes entextualized theoretical discourse, but the sort of craftsman or functionary who translates ideas into the building blocks that make up institutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07: Remembering Medieval Maharashtra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/07_Remembering_Medieval_Maharashtra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/07_Remembering_Medieval_Maharashtra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 7: Remembering Medieval Maharashtra: The Early Seuṇa Yādavas in the World&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The objective of this chapter is to help situate early medieval Maharashtra within the wider purview of the institutional, theological, and political flows that animated the medieval Deccan. In this manner, through a series of intersectional case studies, our exploration will bring into sharp relief the distinctive features of Maharashtra’s medieval religious and political imaginaries prior to the thirteenth century. As we will see, the evidence at hand will eventually call for a reappraisal of Maharashtra’s most famous medieval “Brāhmaṇical” dynasty, the Seuṇa Yādava kings of Devgiri, who will feature with increasing prominence in the final three chapters of the present work. Before we can proceed to offering textured close readings in tandem of image, territory, text, and documentary record, all of which emerge out of our earlier efforts at making sense of the wider Cāḷukya world, first we must grapple with a more fundamental problem. Succinctly, if but briefly, we must confront head on the widespread assumption that, in the absence of extensive textual production, the study of early medieval Maharashtra offers an intrinsic aporia in our understanding about which little of substance can be said. Both in the West and within Maharashtra itself, scholarship that seeks to isolate what is distinctive about Maharashtra gravitates towards a delimited canon of conceptual models. Perhaps the most common frame—running across the political and sectarian spectrum—is to invoke the well-known paradigm of language nationalism.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; From this perspective, [[P893]] Maharashtrian identity is simply treated as coterminous with the history of the Marathi language and its textual production. As will soon be made apparent, however, when Maharashtrian culture is defined by the expressions produced in the Marathi language that were entextualized, the very idea of a Maharashtrian medieval is necessarily called into question. Another, more distinctively sectarian approach of framing the region builds directly upon this framework. By selectively privileging the specific contents of particular registers of textual production in Marathi, “Marathi literature” is seen as epitomizing core shared cultural values, with considerable discrepancies concerning what precisely these might be depending on demographic. Such is the case with the pivotal notion of “Maharashtra dharma,” a topic badly in need of careful historicization. In common parlance the concept is often ascribed—and not entirely without grounds—to the seventeenth-century poet-theologian Rāmadās, remembered as a close associate of Śivājī. In the nationalist discourses of the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries, the term was variously deployed to evoke a martial vision of the restoration of righteous Hindu rule on the one hand, and “a liberal religion eschewing casteist attitudes spread by the poet saints” on the other. In the former register, the privileged canon is comprised of the &lt;em&gt;Dāsabodh&lt;/em&gt; of Rāmadās, the deeds of Śivājī, and the documentary records linking the two. In the latter, in contrast, emphasis is placed on the devotional works that are now held dear by members of the Vārkarī Sampradāya. If in the first key, Maharashtra stands first in the nation in terms of throwing off foreign—especially Islamic—tyranny, a task executed through the cultivation of a certain type of disciplined cultural character, from the second perspective, Maharashtra is imagined as the land of the poet saints—a family of bhaktas drawn from across the spectrum of caste who express their devotion in the specifically Marathi idiom of &lt;em&gt;abhaṅga&lt;/em&gt;, through whose life stories the region is imagined as prelude to the nation. While the imagined progenitor of this movement, the poet saint Jñānadev, who we will encounter in the next chapter, writes at the end of the thirteenth century, as Christian Novetzke and Jon Keune have demonstrated, the constitution of the Vārkarī community in its present form is the product of distinctively early modern acts of memory, performance, and hagiography,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; many of them essentially contemporary with the age of Śivājī.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08: Śākta Cosmopolitanism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/08_shAkta_Cosmopolitanism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/08_shAkta_Cosmopolitanism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 8: Śākta Cosmopolitanism: The Seuṇa Yādava Imaginary Before Hemādri&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-argument-in-search-of-an-archive-problematizing-the-yādava-brāhmaṇical-ecumene&#34;&gt;An Argument in Search of an Archive: Problematizing the Yādava Brāhmaṇical Ecumene&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the opening chapter of his superb work, &lt;em&gt;The Quotidian Revolution&lt;/em&gt;, Christian Novetzke speaks of the “long thirteenth century” (1187–1317 CE) as “the period under Yadava rule [during which]. . . the idea of Maharashtra as a geographic, political, and cultural region fully emerged,” engendering “modern Maharashtra’s origins.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In this regard, he is certainly correct. Novetzke’s intellectual project is primarily invested in making sense of the emergence of Marathi, not strictly speaking as a literary language, but rather as the crucible within which a distinctively Marathi ethos and mode of sociality was beginning to be forged. In contradistinction to “vernacular” forms of literary production in other parts of the subcontinent—such as Telugu or Kannada—which, while setting aside Sanskrit as the medium of expression, remained invested in elite forms of convention-driven literary production, Novetzke argues that early Marathi textuality can be called “the vernacular” for a very different reason. Much as was the case with Martin Luther’s famously earthy potty-mouthed German, in which, for probably the first time in Christian discourse, speculative theology becomes peppered with odes to bodily functions, the shift from Sanskrit to Marathi is not merely a simple matter of a change of tongues—replacing something archaic and elite with a language in common use— but entails a radical reimagining of the parameters of what constitutes written discourse. As Novetzke writes:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09: Universalizing Hindu Dharma</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/09_Universalizing_Hindu_Dharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/09_Universalizing_Hindu_Dharma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 9: Universalizing Hindu Dharma: Hemādri and his Legacy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1: Photo provided courtesy of Temple Trust: Hatnur Nāganātha before the renovation, side view.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reinventing-the-western-deccan-the-seuṇa-sea-change&#34;&gt;Reinventing the Western Deccan: The Seuṇa Sea Change&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2002, in the small town of Hatnur in rural Marathwada, the temple-trust responsible for the management and preservation of the early fourteenth-century Nāganātha temple undertook an ambitious program of renovation and refurbishment. Though the project was meticulously documented, for the historian or even the aficionado of heritage, the end result was something of a mixed blessing. On the one hand, one of the few surviving examples of a completely intact early medieval stone śikhara in the region—which had apparently become structurally unsound—was replaced by a colorful slender spire replicating the style preferred by the Marāṭhas in the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10: Why I Am So Clever</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/10_Why_I_Am_So_Clever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/10_Why_I_Am_So_Clever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 10: Why I Am So Clever, Why I Write Such Excellent Books, and What I Did to the Gods: Hemādri Reimagines Brāhmaṇical Thought&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a manner that has few parallels in the long history of Sanskrit thought, especially in the often-subdued domain of Dharmaśāstra, to read the &lt;em&gt;Caturvargacintāmaṇi&lt;/em&gt; is to stage an encounter with the mind of its author in all his richness of inspiration and many idiosyncrasies. Even after a decade of diligent research seeking out precedents across disciplines and religious boundaries, I have been forced to conclude that while Hemādri is indeed a polymath with access to immense libraries, who may well have known a myriad of intellectual resources now lost to history, both at the level of doctrine and methodology, the most essential features of his work seem to be expressions of his own individual vision and outsized personality. The scope of this accomplishment—that reading Hemādri is to hear one man’s voice—is all the more extraordinary when we take into account that the vast majority of his text is a collection of citations drawn from the writings of other people, sages, and deities, and that even among its enthusiasts, &lt;em&gt;dharmanibandha&lt;/em&gt; is as a genre is almost universally characterized as one of the most colorless discourses in all of Sanskrit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11: Staging Devotional Advaita</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/11_Staging_Devotional_Advaita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/11_Staging_Devotional_Advaita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 11: Staging Devotional Advaita in Thirteenth-Century Maharashtra: Possession, Poetics, and the Anxiety of Influence&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the previous two chapters, we have seen how Hemādri orchestrates a sea-change of values that forever alters the nature and ethos of Hindu law as well as those who practiced it. In the wake of the Caturvargacintāmaṇi, deployed as an operating manual by a new kind of agent acting on behalf of a new kind of state, there is a transformation in the sociology of knowledge—of who has access to what knowledge and under what circumstances, a redistribution of wealth and cultural capital, and substantive alterations in real-world social relations. At the same time, there is also a drastic change in the self-understanding of the religious authorities themselves and the nature of their intellectual production. Throughout the Caturvargacintāmaṇi, Hemādri inserts himself into long-standing conversations introducing new and essentially alien problematics whose founding presuppositions are often fundamentally opposed to the very rules underlying most scholarly language games. The result is that śāstra does not merely have to accommodate new topics, it itself has to become something new. Frequently, such developments entail deploying inherited and often Mīmāṃsā-inflected exegetical technologies and textual practices in the service of very different ends and values. At the center of this new value system stands a reappraisal of affectivity and individual experience. They are suddenly treated as irreducibly philosophical topics of interest that provide us the answers to longstanding epistemological and ontological questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Śaivakālasaṃhārasamkṣiptasāra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/12_shaivakAlasaMhArasamxiptasAra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/12_shaivakAlasaMhArasamxiptasAra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: Śaivakālasaṃhārasamkṣiptasāra&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We began our journey with some provocative questions posed in the early twentieth century by Hazari Prasad Dvivedi that attempted to make sense of Hindu law’s uneasy encounters with colonial modernity. Essentially, Dvivedi discerned that the discourse of Dharmaśāstra contains within itself two mutually exclusive models of legal reasoning. The first of these, which he prizes as an integral dimension of Indic thought, champions the universal application of a fixed set of principles and standards in a logically consistent manner throughout the human realm. In contrast, the second more pluralistic model of site- and community-specific norms— radically internally diversified in terms of its precepts, methods, and core commitments—from his perspective spinelessly abrogated “the rules” of well-ordered human existence to accommodate law and religion to circumstance and changes in context.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Gadyānukramaṇikā</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/13_gadyAnukramaNikA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/13_gadyAnukramaNikA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: Śaivakālasaṃhārasamkṣiptasāra&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chapter 1, “Defamiliarizing the Brāhmaṇical World,” questioned the long-standing tendency to treat conceptual frameworks like “Brāhmaṇism,” “Brāhmaṇical identity,” and “Brāhmaṇical ideology” as trans-historical categories with a fixed and immutable content—as opposed to ones that are historically and geographically contingent, internally contested, and constantly and often self-consciously evolving. On the basis of engagement with a wide range of primary [[P1958]] sources from the classical period, we began to disaggregate “classical Brāhmaṇism,” revealing a range of competing tendencies and social and epistemological visions—different ways of “Being Brāhmaṇa”—already present within Sanskrit discourse. In particular, much as Dvivedi had suggested, an empiricist “Indian way of knowing,” encapsulated in the dictum that one should proceed according to context or circumstances—&lt;em&gt;yathāsthāna&lt;/em&gt;—proved to be as integral to elite Sanskrit knowledge traditions as the more familiar programmatic vision of human action being guided by injunction (&lt;em&gt;yathāvidhi&lt;/em&gt;), where theory as envisioned by elite Brāhmaṇa pandits supposedly always proceeded practice. Moreover, unlike their prescriptivist counterparts, these equally elite conceptualizations of rules and meaning as context-, discipline-, and community-specific proved to be deeply dialogical with the working presuppositions that also animated non-elite social realities and the quotidian experience of everyday life on the subcontinent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/14_Bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/schwartz-jason/shaiva-age-end/14_Bibliography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;primary-sources-in-south-asian-languages&#34;&gt;Primary Sources in South Asian Languages&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Corpus of Inscriptions in the Kannada Districts of Hyderabad State&lt;/em&gt;, Hyderabad Archaeological Series vol. 18, edited by Pandurang Bhimarao Desai. Hyderabad: Archaeological Department, Government of Andhra Pradesh, 1958.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Āgamaprāmāṇya&lt;/em&gt; of Yāmunācārya. Edited by M. Narasimhachary. Baroda: Oriental Institute, 1976.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amṛtasiddhi&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Amṛtasiddhimūla&lt;/em&gt;. Edited and translated by Péter-Dániel Szántó and James Mallinson. Pondicherry: École française d’Extrême-Orient/Institut français de Pondichéry, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“A New Yādava Dynasty.” Edited by Bhagvanlal Indraji. &lt;em&gt;Indian Antiquary&lt;/em&gt; 12 (1883): 119–129.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
