<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;घोराङ्गीरसः on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;घोराङ्गीरसः on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>archaka-classes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/archaka-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/archaka-classes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/890124547244122112&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/890124547244122112&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Felt like re-reading an old judgement: &lt;a href=&#34;https://tinyurl.com/y9pzm28b&#34;&gt;https://tinyurl.com/y9pzm28b&lt;/a&gt; This judgement is not without problems &amp;amp; more than anything bears out the inherent flaws of the constitution. Nonetheless, it was a significant victory that was won for ALL Agamika temples by the Adishaiva priestsA remarkable feature of tamil shaivam and of the broader tamil bhakti movement for which I am yet to observe a parallel elsewhere is the veneration of the shaiva priesthood and the fact that this high veneration was given a canonical status. There may be a parallel in tamil vaiSNava literature - but I&amp;rsquo;m uncertain. But as far as I know, such an admiration for the priesthood as a category of devotees is not to be found elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhakti shAstra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/bhakti-shAstra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/bhakti-shAstra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have often wondered how to express this: In what concrete way can you become better as a result of reading शास्त्र-s or any other sacred texts? An insight dawned upon me when I was reading one of the writings of आऱुमुग नावलर् - the legendary शैव-महाविद्वान् of Jaffna.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The piece in question is titled “नल्लूर्-कन्दस्वामि-कोविल्” (नल्लूर्-स्कन्दस्वामी-आलय). It is essentially a long diatribe in the form of a letter, addressed to the administrators in charge of the स्कन्दस्वामी temple of नल्लूर् (Nallūr) in the year 1875.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book adoration</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/book-adoration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/book-adoration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;स्रोतः - &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1227401091345604608&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1227401091345604608&lt;/a&gt; ।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Regarding the worship of a book by the उष्णीषधारी-s, even this meme, as most would know, has roots in हिंदु-धर्म. Nothing original. We see an example of that from the उत्तरभागा of the कामिकागम, going back to at least 500 years prior to the birth of the शिक्षपान्थी-s’ founder.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There will be a centre for studies (विद्यापीठ) in any of the temple’s 4 cardinal &amp;amp; 4 intermediate directions of the temple, or its inner circuit or, best, in the comforting presence of images of शिवभक्त-s. What materials to use for the book or for the pen? All detailed here. Sacred शैव scriptural wisdom should never be written down by the uninitiated (पशुः, पशवः) or studied in their presence by the wise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dIxA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/dIxA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/dIxA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GhorAngirasa/status/1881664135609610260&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;types&#34;&gt;Types&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Depending on school’s view, Viśeșa or Nirvāņa Dīkșā opens up one for Ātmārthapūjā (I align with the view that the latter Dīkșā is required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is consensus that Nirvāņadīkșā opens one up to Sādhakābhișeka or Ācāryābhișeka, if there are additional qualifications which are met.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, Nirvāņadīkșā, combined with adherence to Samayācāra (which includes Ātmārthapūjā), leads a soul to Paramukti after death.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But in either case - in this system whatever level of Saiva Diksha a sishya receives - Adhikara for Pararatha Puja in Devalaya only comes with those who are of specific Jati?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geo-connection</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/geo-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/geo-connection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GhorAngirasa/status/960617695174627328&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The threads that connect bhArata are the threads of dharma; and nothing else. Many of these threads are obscure, deep, remote, profound &amp;amp; beautiful. The more obscure the link, the more delightful and beautiful it becomes. I&amp;rsquo;ll briefly present one such example in following tweets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll see a link of the most obscure (and thus, pleasurable) kind linking two lands, which are both part of the akhaNDabhArata in all its glory, and could not possibly be further: kAshmIradesha &amp;amp; yavadvIpa, which is&amp;hellip;.all the way at Java (yava) in Indonesia! At the very hoary beginnings of the noble siddhAnta shaiva tradition in that pristine land of kAshmIradesha, there was a debate about the aSTa vidyeshvara-s, eight supreme beings directly only below sadAshiva and above everyone else. They are considered practically shiva himself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gochara names</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/gochara-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/gochara-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/useoneonly/status/1984097220740968809&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-gocharas&#34;&gt;5 gocharas&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Gocaras are Śiva, Jyoti, Šikha and Savitra. Each is subdivided in accordance with the division between the disciplines [of the Brahmacarin, Grhastha, Vanaprastha and Bhiksu)&amp;hellip;. Persons carry the name of the Gocara of those who have initiated them, while the religious regimes of the [four] disciplines [adopted within each] are a matter of personal choice. These names [ending in -siva, -jyotis, etc.] are proper to brahmins. The names of Ksatriyas [, Vaisyas] and [Śūdras] are distinguished by the [ending] -gana, while all women are required to have names [ending] in-sakti.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>graha-pUjA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/graha-pUjA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/graha-pUjA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have asked this question on various forums: &amp;ldquo;Why are there navagrahas only in Śiva temples governed by siddhānta-āgama-s?&amp;rdquo; The answer hit me a while ago when I realized that the navagrahas worshiped by Śaiva-s are not the ones we know in this Brahmāṇḍa (which consists of this entire material universe, svarga, naraka-s, asura, rākṣasa, yakṣa, gandharva worlds, etc), which is in Pṛthivī-tattva.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From Pṛthivī-tattva (lowest of 36 tattva-s) to Puruṣa-tattva is the Aśuddhādhvan (&amp;ldquo;impure&amp;rdquo; pathway of the cosmos made of Aśuddhamāyā). Above Aśuddhamāyā is the Śuddhādhvan (the pure pathway), which consists of Śuddhavidyā, Īśvara, Sadāśiva, Śakti and Śiva-tattvas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guru limitations</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/guru-limitations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/guru-limitations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GhorAngirasa/status/1917842734788010344&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Guru or Ācārya doesn’t have to be omniscient to impart potent metaphysical truths.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He can, in fact, be wrong about historical or other factual issues and yet be able to impart spiritual statements which are potent and can lead one to an obtainable Ādhyātmika end.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is also no connection between a Guru’s mantrasiddhi and his accuracy in both laukika and atilaukika matters. A guru can have animādi siddhis and still be parviscient.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>navarAtryutsavaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/navarAtryutsavaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/navarAtryutsavaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1317838683861442560.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The सिद्धान्त-शैव significance of नवरात्री for शैव-s:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the वामदेव-मन्त्र of the पञ्चब्रह्म-मन्त्र-s (5 वैदिक/आगमिक मन्त्र-s for 5 complete, undivided modes of सदाशिव), the sages of the सिद्धान्त extracted the names of 9 देवी-s:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;वामा&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ज्येष्ठा&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;रौद्री&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;काली&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;कलविकरणी&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;बलविकरणी&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;बलप्रमथनी&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;सर्वभूतदमनी&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;मनोन्मनी&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are the 9 शक्ति-s who represent the various potencies of सदाशिव (in his mode as वामदेव) in his lordship of the impure universe (अशुद्ध-अध्वा, अशुद्धाध्वा). Where the पौराणिक-शैव or स्मार्त or शाक्त sees the significance in 9 दुर्गा-s, one whose mind is attached to the सिद्धान्त-शास्त्र understands these to be the 9 वामादि-शक्ति-s embedded in the वामदेव-मन्त्र.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platonic formulation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/platonic-formulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/platonic-formulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GhorAngirasa/status/1932593018848297114&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This goes well with the Saiddhāntika conception of Ātmā (Self/Soul) &amp;amp; its inseparable Cicchakti (which is the Ātmā’s individuality). Every Ātmā, when divested of all non-innate, insentient characteristics (form, name, māyā which supplies it with the stream of bodies/faculties through births, karmic baggage, etc), is a unique sentient, whose fundamental nature cannot be further simplified.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was also trying to formulate, yesterday night, the “categorical”/“univeraal” Śivatvam as an analog of the One before I decided to write this morning:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rudrAxa-niyamaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/rudrAxa-niyamaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/rudrAxa-niyamaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GhorAngirasa/status/1860955400541200537&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;śrī-śiva-mahā-purāṇe prathamāyāṃ vidyeśvarasaṃhitāyāṃ sādhyasādhanakhaṇḍe rudrākṣamahātmyavarṇanonāma pañcaviṃśo&amp;rsquo;dhyāyaḥ|&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Śivamahāpurāṇa - Vidyeśvarasaṁhitā - 25th Adhyāya (Rudrākṣa-Māhātmya-Varṇana: Description of Rudrākṣa’s glory&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;paṃcabrahmabhir aṃgaśca trimālāṃ paṃcasapta ca |&#xA;athavā mūlamaṃtreṇa sarvān akṣāṃs tu dhārayet || 42 ||&#xA;42. With five mantras—Sadyojāta etc. three, five or seven garlands shall be worn. Or all beads shall be worn with the Mūla mantra[8].&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;madyaṃ māṃsaṃ tu laśunaṃ palāṇḍuṃ śigrumeva ca |&#xA;śleṣmāṃtakaṃ viḍvarāhaṃ bhakṣaṇe varjayettataḥ || 43 ||&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ShivAchArya fortune</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/shivAchArya-fortune/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/shivAchArya-fortune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will make a remark. सिद्धान्ती अर्चक-s are truly very blessed among temple priesthoods. While आगमिक priesthoods in general are vastly more resourced in giving a proper basis for their rituals, I have always felt that सिद्धान्ती-s went many an extra mile in this direction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am not too sure how many सिद्धान्त-शिवाचार्य-s follow me here. Perhaps, less than 5. In any case, I hope how fortunate they are. And I will explain it very briefly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shivAlaya-dharmakartA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/shivAlaya-dharmakartA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/shivAlaya-dharmakartA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Śaivālaya Dharmakartā (शैवालय-धर्मकर्ता)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By Uttaramērūr Tamiḻ-Paṇḍita Siddhānta-Paṇḍita-Bhūṣaṇam Śrīmān Ā. Īśvaramūrti-Pillai (उत्तरमेरूर् तमिऴ्-पण्डितर् श्रीमान् आ. ईश्वरमूर्ति-पिळ्ळै)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Year of Publication: 1940&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro-by-translator&#34;&gt;Intro by translator&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have translated his 16-point essay in Tamizh on the qualifications &amp;amp; duties of an ideal धर्मकर्ता i.e. temple administrator. It may be interesting to take a look at this (now) historical document in the light of recent debates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While several points are शैव-centric, you can read them mutatis mutandis (That is, you can rephrase the शैव points for yourself in another specific framework or a generic one). This, of course, is left to the readers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temple making in kAmikAgama</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/temple-making-kAmikAgama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/temple-making-kAmikAgama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/929056965413744641&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/929056965413744641&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The greatest gift of rituals is the reverence it instills in us; not just for the deity but for all beings, all communities. The Agamika tradition involved a number of rites where different individuals (even animals) were honored. Let us see some verses from the kAmikAgamaThe kAmikAgama does not simply concern itself with rituals at temple. After all, the prerequisite for temple worship is, well, a temple which has been built.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ugra mUrtis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/ugra-mUrtis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/ugra-mUrtis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;4 forms of Vișņu are singled out as examples of Ugra Vișņumūrtis in Śrīmat-Kāmikāgama: Viśvarūpa, Vațapatraśāyī, Narasimha &amp;amp; Paraśurāma (&amp;amp; the first two can be seen as particularly Kārșņeya forms).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These forms + Bhagavān’s Ugramūrtis (Gajāri, Kāmāri, Kālāri &amp;amp; Tripurāri) are recommended to be kept at the village’s outskirts in the north-east.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>varNAshrama-dharmaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/varNAshrama-dharmaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/varNAshrama-dharmaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a synopsis of Shaiva Siddhant in tritiya paad of Narad Puran.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Adhyāya even paraphrases, IIRC, a lost śloka from Bhārgavottara, a lost Siddhāntāgama:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;varṇāśramācārān&lt;br&gt;&#xA;manasāpi na laṅghayet ||&lt;br&gt;&#xA;yo yasminnāśrame tiṣṭhan&lt;br&gt;&#xA;prāpto dīkṣāṃ śivātmikām |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;sa tasminneva saṃtiṣṭhan&lt;br&gt;&#xA;śivadharmaṃ ca pālayet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dravidoid-subversion&#34;&gt;Dravidoid subversion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GhorAngirasa/status/960617695174627328&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A good question. Current ecosystem of siddhAnta in TN has been hijacked to a significant extent by dravidianist ideologues who portray shaiva siddhAnta as the &amp;ldquo;original dravidian religion&amp;rdquo; that was destroyed by Aryan vedism&amp;hellip;.Nevertheless, the proper tradition still survives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VidyA-deha chatus saMskAra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/vidyA-deha_chatus-saMskAra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/vidyA-deha_chatus-saMskAra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our worship is performed with our bodies, sensory &amp;amp; cognitive instruments &amp;amp; the physical objects (including the offerings/dravya), which are insentient, destructible &amp;amp; amenable to modifications. This is why a Siddhanti has to not only purify his body &amp;amp; internal faculties with mantras (&amp;amp; prepare something known as a Vidyādeha) but has to consecrate the offerings such as food &amp;amp; flowers (which are insentient) with a rite known as Catussaṁskāra, whereby Cit is made to manifest in those insentient substances, as Cit (which is what every Atma really is) is the perfect offering for Paramasiva who is Cidghana.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>पीठ-पादाः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/pITha-pAdAH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/kriyA/GA/pITha-pAdAH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thread by @GhorAngirasa –&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The पञ्चासन of सैद्धान्तिक ritual - A &amp;ldquo;super-throne&amp;rdquo; made of five layers. So, one can see the four lions on one of the layers (the सिंहासन layer of the पञ्चासन).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is the significance of these four lions?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The 4 lions are धर्म, ज्ञान, वैराग्य &amp;amp; ऐश्वर्य. This is clear.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, in the साङ्ख्या, these 4 are the भाव-s of the बुद्धि, apart from the 4 counterparts: अधर्म, अज्ञान, अवैराग्य &amp;amp; अनैश्वर्य.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
