<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Indic spread</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/articles/indic-spread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/articles/indic-spread/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1792075624808681573.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many H, if they have heard of the Śaiva Siddhānta at all, are supposed Śaivam to be a uniquely Tamilian theological school with its origins in the 13th century—a school that has a body of only in Tamil theological works but how true is it? 🧵&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While, it is true that Siddhānta has primary survived in recent centuries only in the Tamil region, but while the Tamils developed this tradition and enriched and modified it in various ways over the centuries, it was certainly not a Tamil creation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mikael-conversion - hindu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/articles/mikael-conversion_hindu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/articles/mikael-conversion_hindu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;India, his beacon of light&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Denmark’s Mikael Stamm in his search for philosophical answers ended up doing his Ph.D in Śaiva Siddhanta at the University of Madras.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Suganthy Krishnamachari&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mikael Stamm, scholar from Denmark, in Chennai. Photo: B. Jothi Ramalingam&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Philosopher Hume wrote that books on metaphysics contained nothing but “sophistry and illusion.” Most analytic philosophers were inspired by Hume’s condemnation of metaphysics. The logical positivists even tried to develop artificial languages, which, by their very nature, would make it impossible for metaphysical questions to be asked in those languages. The Vienna circle, which not only included philosophers such as Neurath, Schlick and Carnap, but also mathematicians such as Godel, also wanted to steer clear of metaphysics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mp maThas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/articles/mp-maThas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/articles/mp-maThas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;sarasvatipattanam&#34;&gt;sarasvatIpaTTanam&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most important Śaiva Siddhāntika (Maṭṭamayūra) Maṭha of Surwaya (ancient Sarasvatīpattana, Madhya Pradesh) built probably around c. 700-800 CE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Siddhantika monarchism was not limited to Kadwaha alone; other locations also played significant role in creating and strengthening the movement aided by the maṭhas that served as strongholds of the sages. While Kadwaha grew in prominence acquiring ever-new frontiers of material space in terms of territories its branches occupied other sites both in the near or distant regions, and their ācāryas too did not lag behind either in power or in glory. Forest tracts seem to have been their major attraction and they are found securing them without let.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nandanAr</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/articles/nandanAr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/articles/nandanAr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1267279686209466369.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So what exactly is the Nandanar story. Unfortunately the Nandhanar Charititam written by Gopalakrishna Bharatiyar went too far from the original history as mentioned in Sekkizhar’s Periya Puranam, which is the authentic source as far as the 63 Śaiva Saints are concerned. Why did Gopalakrishna deviate so much and added so much of ‘masala’ is anybody’s guess. What is more appalling is that the legendary SS Vasan made a movie straight out of this story line &amp;amp; popularised. Thus this one stayed as if it was the correct version.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tamil-maTha-status</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/articles/tamil-maTha-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/28-Agama-sampradAyaH/articles/tamil-maTha-status/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/tamil_shaivam/status/1795867491950014881&#34;&gt;bhuvanesh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;non-tamil-roots&#34;&gt;Non tamiL roots&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 4 ancient siddhantha mutts ranabhadra,pushpagiri,golaki and amardaka were actually in north and not in tamil land.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kamalai NjanaPrakashar, the guru of gurujnanasambandhar (the sthapakacharya of dharumai aadhinam) undegone study on siddhantha in gauda desa.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;diversity-loss&#34;&gt;Diversity loss&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even in shaiva siddhantha there are different schools of thought. Post meykandar,other inner sampradayas started to diminish. many mathas accepted meykandar theology and some tradition just stopped&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The meykandar school of siddhantha shaivam is called so because it&amp;rsquo;s dominant in the the tamil land. There&amp;rsquo;s a saiva matha named vallalar aadhinam they follow aikyavaada saiva.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
