<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>शैवतन्त्रे मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्लेखाः on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in शैवतन्त्रे मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्लेखाः on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The vyomavyApin mantra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2008-02-10_the-vyomavyapin-mantra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2008-02-10_the-vyomavyapin-mantra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2008/02/10/the-vyomavyapin-mantra/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The celebrated mantra of the Urdhva srotas, the vyomvyApin comprises of 368 syllables. Below is the version I am familiar with. Examination of 3 manuscripts vy1 from Chidambaram, vy2 from Madurai and vy3 from Tiruvatuturai reveals certain variations from version I have. I have thus far not been able to lay my hands on the surviving Kashmirian manuscripts of the same. The deletion in the same place in the vy1 and vy2 manuscripts appear to result from a break in the original leaf from which both were likely to have been copied. Some of these variants might probably be used validly. An oral version of a shaiva priest I observed had certain further peculiarities, which could all be attributed to errors due to the linguistic distortions produced by the influence of drAviDa bhASha.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1st person rudra experience</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/first-person-rudra-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/first-person-rudra-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1445246256423620610&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1445246256423620610&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is this tantalizing fragment from the nishvAsaguhya where where nandin is explaining the pa~nchabrahma as per the vaimala &amp;amp; saiddhAntika tradition to a v1 interlocutor&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;पञ्च-मन्त्रमयं देवं पञ्च-मन्त्र-शरीरिणम्।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;पञ्चमन्त्र &amp;hellip; मन्त्र &amp;hellip; सदाशिवम् ||&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there are lacunae in the text &amp;amp; the next sentence is mostly lost but it seems to describe shiva&amp;rsquo;s form as made up of the 5-brahma-s. nandin clearly lays out the objectives of the deployment of 5:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An early shaiva formula</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-05-12_an-early-shaiva-formula/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-05-12_an-early-shaiva-formula/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Very little is preserved of the ancestral tantric shaiva lineage prior&#xA;to its split into the five fold path. An early formula of the lineage&#xA;that survives is seen in the garuDa tantra termed hara tantram, which&#xA;itself does not survive as a full text as far as I know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The distinctive core used to make the oblation for rudra in the fire is&#xA;thus:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amantrito .asi devesha gaNaiH sArdhaM maheshvara |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;prAtastvAM pUjayiShyAmi atra sannihito bhava |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(Invitation to rudra with his agents to the rite)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BhUta srotas misc</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/bhUta-srotas_misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/bhUta-srotas_misc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1942426912439050420&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The bhUtasrotas specifies that the practitioner of the bhUta-tantra-s should wear a bracelet that makes ghosts tremble. It is described thus:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;puShpa-lohamayaM divyaM&lt;br&gt;&#xA;bIjAkSharair alaMkR^itaM ||&#xA;vAma-haste tu kaTakaM&lt;br&gt;&#xA;dhArayet bhUta-kaMpanaM |&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The bracelet or bangle is said to be made of puShpa-loha, worn on the left arm and stamped with bIjAkShara-s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is puShpaloha? It is a rare word that is primarily only found in a few shaiva tantra-s and several times in the bauddha ma~njushrIya mUlakalpa. There, in addition to bracelets, tridents and swords are also made from it. It also suggests a connection with the gaNa of rudra named lohaka, who is prominent in the bhUtasrotas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brahma yAmala srotas listing</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/brahma-yAmala-srotas-listing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/brahma-yAmala-srotas-listing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1779386427584757918&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some of the brahmayAmala transmission state:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;गारुडे भूततन्त्रे तु&lt;br&gt;&#xA;बाल-तन्त्रे तु भैरवि ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;नय-सिद्धान्त-तन्त्र-स्थे&lt;br&gt;&#xA;साधकाः संप्रयोजितः ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;कुरुते सर्वकर्माणि न&lt;br&gt;&#xA;च सङ्करताम् व्रजेत् ।&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is curious in multiple ways, though it is possible the verses are corrupt. Of the 5 srotAMsi the bhUta, garuDa and siddhAnta are clear. But bhairava and vAma are missing. Since naya-nayottara are part of the vAma canon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is likely that naya is vAma.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;But bAla is never associated with bhairava.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Instead, it may be identified with the rAvaNa&amp;amp; kaumAra tantra-s that&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>chIna daiva dice</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/chIna-daiva-dice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/chIna-daiva-dice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1462648749566668800&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1462648749566668800&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The chIna daiva dice like those used in maheshvara magic. Such prognostic magic ultimately had their roots in H tradition though the link has has been forgotten. The maheshvara magic and garuDa (pUrvasrotas)-tantra derived texts indicate the presence of shaiva (&amp;amp; kaumAra)traditions in east Asia. While initial transmitted by tAthAgata-s like amoghavajra, they acquired a life of their own as cults. e.g. &amp;ldquo;jialouluo ji zhutian miyan jing&amp;rdquo; = scripture of Mantras of garuDa and gods seems to be 1 transmission of garuDa-tantra material by a Kashmirian.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coexistence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/coexistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/coexistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Without elaborating, I still think JS&amp;rsquo;s view seems to overemphasize or even make the bhairavasrotas/kaula dominance exclusive. That said, when we take the evidence from throughout the country I think at the great kShetra-s the different branches of the shaiva-shAsana simultaneously existed. We see this at the great siddhAnta-dominated temple centers in the drAviDa country; we see it Nepal and Kashmir.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moreover, rAmakaNTha-II&amp;rsquo;s mata~NgapArameshvara commentary suggests that siddhAnta tantra-s were being accepted and interpreted  as per their internal tradition by even by non-saiddhAntika-s. I take this to imply a general socially dominant saiddhantika substrate among whom various shaiva schools still persisted and in some cases ascended.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dvijas and non-dvijas in the shaiva cults</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2005-03-26_dvijas-and-non-dvijas-in-the-shaiva-cults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2005-03-26_dvijas-and-non-dvijas-in-the-shaiva-cults/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we argued earlier the kAlAmukhas were rather orthodox, even if&#xA;electic, followers of the Astika path. Their intellectual prelidictions&#xA;were rather clear, and they philosophical abilities are also strongly&#xA;suggested from what material that survives of the shakti pariShad,&#xA;mainly in the Kannada country, and the siMha parishad in the Andhra and&#xA;Tamil country. Their Kashmirian precursors were also strongly&#xA;intellectual brahmins (the kAshmira paNDitas of the inscriptions) who&#xA;originally coexisted with their cousins who were proponents of other&#xA;tantric schools like shrikula and trika. This is in contrast with the&#xA;stark unorthodoxy of the Lingayatas or vIrashaivas who followed them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of dakShiNashaiva system</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2010-01-05_a-discursion-on-the-sanatkumariya-panchabrahma-siddha-shamkara-tantra-and-the-early-evolution-of-the-dakshinashaiva-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2010-01-05_a-discursion-on-the-sanatkumariya-panchabrahma-siddha-shamkara-tantra-and-the-early-evolution-of-the-dakshinashaiva-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;लेखकः - &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;मनसतरङ्गिणीकारः&lt;/a&gt;।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/24766652@N05/4259390457/&#34; title=&#34;kalinjar_bhairavas2 by somasushma, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/farm5.static.flickr.com/4031/4259390457_2140b69189.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/farm5.static.flickr.com/4031/4259390457_2140b69189.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kalinjar_bhairavas2&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diversity and syncretism in the bhairava or dakShiNa srotas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The bhairava-srotas of the shaiva mantramArga was clearly one of the&#xA;most speciose branches of the shaiva-shAsana. From the ancestral&#xA;bhairava-srotas base that itself most probably arose from the&#xA;kApAlika-oriented streams of the underlying shaiva atimArga the system&#xA;spawned several distinctive branches: 1) An early branch was the&#xA;dakShiNashaiva stream centered around the worship of svachChanda&#xA;bhairava; 2) the system of kapAlIsha bhairava mainly taught in the&#xA;archaic brahma-yAmala (distinct from the later brahma yAmala of the&#xA;drAviDa country). The influence of the yoginI-kula system, an early&#xA;representative of which was the kaula-j~nAna-nirNaya of matsyendra,&#xA;resulted in several distinct kaula systems of the bhairava-srotas (these&#xA;could be colloquially termed “shAkta” influenced): 3) the trika system&#xA;originally with the triadic bhairava-s (ratishekhara, bhairava-sadbhAva,&#xA;navAtman) and their shakti-s (parAparA, parA and aparA) or the bhairava&#xA;shabdarAshi and his shaktI mAlinI. This is expounded in the tantra-s&#xA;beginning with the siddhayogeshvarI-mata. 4) The kAlIkulA or the krama&#xA;system which is associated with tantra-s such as&#xA;kalIkula-pa~nchashataka and the mantra system of the early&#xA;pA~ncharAtra-influenced deity kAlasaMkarShaNI (who is one of the&#xA;evolutes of the old ekAnaMshA). 5) The kubjikA-mata taught in the system&#xA;stemming from the saMvartAmaNDala sUtra-s. This stream shared an early&#xA;evolutionary history with the trikA system. 6) The shrIkula system which&#xA;has many distinct varieties such as the nine nityA-s and kAmashiva, 11&#xA;vilAsinI-s, tripurabhairavI, bAlA, tripurasundarI and the 16 nityA-s and&#xA;Ananda bhairava, kameshvarI and kAmeshvara. 7) In addition to these, the&#xA;bhairava srotas underwent a syncretic development with a much earlier&#xA;independent stream of the mantra-mArga, i.e. the worship of&#xA;mR^ityu~njaya. This resulted in the system of amR^iteshvara bhairava&#xA;and amR^iteshvarI which is expounded by the netra tantra. Also in this&#xA;stream is the special worship of amR^iteshvara and svachChanda bhairava&#xA;(in one of two forms, sakala-bhaTTAraka or niShkala-bhaTTAraka) with&#xA;their shakti-s in the bhairava chakra-s drawn from the svachChanda&#xA;system. Further, the netra-tantra has a secret chapter known as&#xA;mahAbhichAra for the performance of fierce abhichAra rituals that is not&#xA;present in the published version. This section of only taught within the&#xA;tradition of the dIkShita-s of the netra system and primarily concerns&#xA;the homa-s to a combined form of amR^iteshvara and svachChanda known as&#xA;mahAbhairava in the tradition. Other syncretic traditions of the&#xA;bhairava srotas include: 8) the system of AkAsha bhairava, which&#xA;represents a combination of the bhairava srotas with the earlier&#xA;garuDa-srotas and 9) the “extant” jayadratha yAmala which presents&#xA;itself as a version of the original shirashCheda that was transmitted as&#xA;a combination of the vAma and bhairava streams (rather than the pure&#xA;vAma system as taught in the vINAshikhA tantra with tumburu and his 4&#xA;sisters, i.e. the ancient chatur-bhagini system). The voluminous&#xA;yoga-vAsiShTha also alludes to the combined worship of tumburu of the&#xA;vAma-srotas along with bhairava in the midst of the mAtR^I chakra with&#xA;yoginI-s like alambushA, suggesting that this vAmA-bhairava syncretism&#xA;was also once popular (nirvANa prakaraNa 18.26; chapter 18 has a&#xA;description of shiva and the mAtR^ikA-s). Likewise, certain lineages of&#xA;the bhairava-srotas, mainly that of svachChanda bhairava, also influence&#xA;the Urdhvas-srotas or the siddhAnta tradition. For example, IshAnashiva,&#xA;somashambhu and vishvanAtha in their ritual manuals use the&#xA;prescriptions of the svachChanda-bhairava tantra. 10) The raseshvara&#xA;system is an offshoot of the older svachaChanda bhairava system that was&#xA;centered on the tradition of rasa-siddhas. Its central deity&#xA;rasabhairava and his shakti rasA~nkushI are emanations of svachChanda&#xA;bhairava and his shakti aghoreshvarI. 11) Some texts like the&#xA;brahma-yAmala hold a view that there is an additionally adhaH srotas&#xA;which deal with the vaiShNava tantra-s pertaining to nR^isiMha. Some of&#xA;these appear to be influenced by the bhairava srotas via the more&#xA;ancient rudra-nR^isiMha equivalence. In another definition the adhaH&#xA;srotas is supposed to contain the tradition of hATakeshvara. A text&#xA;called the AnandAdhikAra tantra is said to be a part of this tradition&#xA;by abhinavagupta but it does not apparently survive. This srotas seem to&#xA;be a later addition to the original system, mainly within the traditions&#xA;arising from the original bhairava srotas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frequency evolution</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/frequency-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/frequency-evolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1539078225044946945.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;spreadsheet&#34; src=&#34;../shaiva-term-frequency.tsv&#34; fullHeightWithRowsPerScreen=8&gt; &lt;/div&gt;  &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A table of frequency of certain keywords across 6 shaiva-tantra-s. For each text the 1st column is absolute count; 2nd is rank (ties randomly broken); 3rd is frequency relative to the most frequent word. This provides insights into the post-vaidika evolution of the tradition&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 1st text is uDDAmareshvara, TMK, the best preserved of the extant DAmara tantra-s. It shows a clear dominance of rudra, an absence of sadAshiva &amp;amp; the other names being roughly equally distributed. This is closer to the vaidika name space &amp;amp; it shows mantra-s of an archaic form that are reminiscent &amp;amp; in some cases directly related the those from the uchChuShma-rudra-kalpa of the atharvan tradition. Thus, it may be inferred to be from an early stratum of the shaiva tradition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From the parAtrIshikhA section of the rudra yAmala</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2005-03-21_from-the-paratrishikha-section-of-the-rudra-yamala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2005-03-21_from-the-paratrishikha-section-of-the-rudra-yamala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Hindu world view ritual and philosophy are intimately linked.&#xA;From the substratum of the shrauta ritual the ancient upaniShads arise.&#xA;From the matrix of the tantras the highest kaulika thought emerges. Only&#xA;one who can fully internalize this organic connection between the ritual&#xA;perform and philosophy, can truly grasp the language and thought of the&#xA;ancient Hindu. While the veda and the mantra-tantra shAstra may appear&#xA;superficially very distinct they are unified by the same underlying&#xA;entwinement of ritual practice and philosophical contemplation. They&#xA;unified by the same discoveries of the ancient Hindu linguists and the&#xA;geometric thought of the archaic Indo-Europeans. In one of the surviving&#xA;fragments of the rudra yAmala is seen the basis of kaulika thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>garbhanyAsaH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/garbhanyAsaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/garbhanyAsaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1636923954131529729&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A shaiva deposit box from the champa kingdom, likely the 1100s during the reign of jaya harivarman &amp;ndash; the garbhanyAsa of the pratiShTha-tantra-s with vR^iShabha-s&amp;amp; either the bhuvaneshvara-s or vidyeshvara-s. The deposit with various items was placed beneath the site of the temple.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The garbhanyAsa is performed after the prathameShTaka-nyAsa where 4 bricks corresponding to the 1st step in the actual temple construction are laid. It connects the pratiShTha ritual to the vaidika piling of chiti-s with first layer of bricks &amp;amp; a deposit with 5 heads including in old practice, a freshly severed human head obtained from a cemetery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>goraxa-sampradAya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/goraxa-sampradAya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/goraxa-sampradAya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GorakSha is rather unanimously acknowledged as a student/successor of matsyendra in the pan-Indian nAtha tradition. A lot of patina has developed around his historical personage &amp;amp; sometimes he is depicted as even a bit of rival to his mentor. But can we say anything serious about the original gorakSha?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;pashchimamnaya&#34;&gt;pashchimAMnAya&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His teacher matsyendra can be, with reasonable certainty, regarded as an early or even foundational kaula teacher. The kaula-j~nAna-nirNaya can be seen as text with him as the author of the core. Hence, we can say that he was specifically aligned with the pashchimAMnAya. However, his influence was certainly accepted among the other AMnAya-s, e.g., the kashmirian mantravAdin, abhinavagupta, who was aligned with the pUrvAMnAya. In a similar vein we posit that the original gorakSha was a solidly in the pashchimAMnAya tradition &amp;amp; a major teacher of that tradition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kuNDalinI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/kuNDalinI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/kuNDalinI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1727589535125483948&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the oldest layer of the pashcimAMnAya the manifestation of the goddess rudrashakti or the ascent of kuNDalinI was quite impetuous. It is noted as triggering trembling, shaking, falling into a lucid dream sleep, visions of netherworlds, prancing on one limb, xenoglossy, jumping like an antelope, roaring like a lion and crying with tears. The yoga of the later layers (e.g., saundaryalaharI) and the dakShiNAMnAya succeeded in considerably taming the process and the Avesha elements considerably reduced or entirely vanished.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mRgayAtrA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/mRgayAtrA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/mRgayAtrA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The account in the choLa age ritual manual of aghorashiva &amp;ndash; mahotsava-vidhi and the compendium the mahotsava-Agama-shekhara indicate that mR^igayAtra it was a real hunt a implied &amp;ndash; this is also implied by the shaivAgama-s that mention it. e.g. mR^igendra. They don&amp;rsquo;t say mock.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also mentioned in Darapuram choLa inscription from south Arcot. This inscription is in tanjAvur not far from where my ancestors lived 2 centuries ago.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The military paraphernalia &amp;amp; hunting &amp;ndash; hunts were military exercises among both Indians &amp;amp; mongols. Yes &amp;ndash; the armaments are explicitly mention both in the ritual texts&amp;amp; Agama-s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>netra tantraM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-06-24_some-words-on-the-netra-tantram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-06-24_some-words-on-the-netra-tantram/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;लेखकः - &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;मनसतरङ्गिणीकारः&lt;/a&gt;।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;tryambakaṃ yajāmahe sugandhiṃ puṣṭi vardhanam&lt;br&gt;&#xA;urvārukam iva bandhanān mṛtyor mukṣīya māmṛtāt&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The netra tantra commented upon by the famous kShema-rAja, student of&#xA;abhinava-gupta, is of some what later origin amongst the shaiva tantras.&#xA;It is not listed as a primary text in any of the five srotas of the&#xA;tantric shaiva mArga in support of this contention. However, it was&#xA;definitely considered cannonical by the start of the syncretic trika&#xA;period. While it has affinities with the garuDa tantras, there is&#xA;evidence to believe that the netra tantra tradition was a parallel&#xA;stream outside the five cannonical srotas that probably branched from an&#xA;ancestor close to the garuDa srotas but evolved on its own in the midst&#xA;of the kaTha yajurvedin brAhmaNas of northern and north-western India.&#xA;The main evidence for the connection to the garuDa srotas is from its&#xA;emphasis on the mR^ityunjaya mantra which is also expounded in the&#xA;former tantras. In support of this we note that kShemarAja uses quotes&#xA;from the garuDa srotas to explain several points in the netra tantraM,&#xA;and the mantra of tryaMbaka rudra as amR^iteshvara, which is the central&#xA;theme of the tantra. The worship of mR^ityunjaya or amR^iteshvara has a&#xA;very precise iconography that is described in the dhyAna shloka given in&#xA;the 3rd paTala (chapter) of the netra tantra. R brought to my attention&#xA;a couple of idols of tryaMbaka or amR^iteshvara and his wife, one from&#xA;what is now Himachal Pradesh (close to R’s native village) and one from&#xA;what is now Afghanistan (where apparently kaTha yajurvedins were once&#xA;present). These exactly match the dhyAna sholkas supporting the&#xA;importance of this stream as an independent one in N/NW India. Further,&#xA;the kaTha brAhmaNa tAntrika-s use the important double prayoga, the&#xA;aghora prayoga and the tryaMbaka prayoga with the mantras of svachChanda&#xA;bhairava and amR^iteshvara. Importantly, the kaTha-s before reciting&#xA;their shatarudriya recite the dhyAna sholkas of tryaMbaka and aghora–&#xA;somewhat akin to the insertion the taittirIya yajurvedin-s make after&#xA;the first rudrAnuvAka in shaiva recitation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Royal kumAra worshippers</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2005-10-28_royal-kumara-worshippers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2005-10-28_royal-kumara-worshippers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;लेखकः - &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;मनसतरङ्गिणीकारः&lt;/a&gt;।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Shunga coins: The late Maurya and Shunga period has the square coins&#xA;of the Ujjain series bearing the image of kumAra. They installed some&#xA;idols of kumAra in Mathura (175-50 BC).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Shakas:&lt;/strong&gt; The Shaka king Ayalisha (Azilises-I) has kumAra on his&#xA;coin. Another Indianized Shaka mentions construction of a well in the&#xA;name of skanda. The exact date of this inscription is unclear: mentioned&#xA;as year 201 in some era.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rudra-gAyatrI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/rudra-gAyatrI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/rudra-gAyatrI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1718488091780849934&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only &amp;ldquo;sAvitrI-form&amp;rdquo; gAyatrI found in the RV saMhitA is the sAvitrI of viShvAmitra. Same is true for the taittirIya-saMhitA. In the kaTha-saMhitA it is the grammatically peculiar rudra-gAyatrI. In the maitrAyaNIya the rudra-gAyatrI serves as locus for a long late interpolation. This interpolation is homologous to what appears to be a similar interpolation in the taittirIya-AraNyaka. But the taittirIya-AraNyaka preserved a distinct, grammatically peculiar sAvitrI-form rudra-gAyatrI. This leads to the speculation that the first sAvitrI-form gAyatrI to be&#xA;conceived was likely the rudra-gAyatrI among group of early shaiva, perhaps associated with the performers of the vrAtya rituals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some considerations on the tantric path</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2005-11-15_some-considerations-on-the-tantric-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2005-11-15_some-considerations-on-the-tantric-path/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to put down some matters arising in the discourse with R&#xA;during the winding train journey.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following are listed as authoritative tantras by the great trika&#xA;tantrics:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;1) kAmika 2) kiraNa 3) niHshvAsa 4) pauShkara 5) raurava 6) svAyambhuva&#xA;7) pArameshvara.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;These may be termed the proper shaivAgamas&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(some of these contain important details concerning the pa~nchAkShari&#xA;of mahAdeva, of which another aspirant had made some recent enquiries to&#xA;me).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sundaranAtha (tirumUlar)’s lineage</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-08-25_sundaranatha-tirumulars-lineage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-08-25_sundaranatha-tirumulars-lineage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the preamble to the tirumantiraM tirumUlar (verses ) gives his&#xA;lineage thus (translated only loosely during conversation with my&#xA;clansmen who know the drAviDa bhASha/transliterated from a reading in an&#xA;old book possessed by them):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;n^an^dhi aruLpeRRa n^Adharai n^ADiDin&lt;br&gt;&#xA;seek the nAtha-s (tantric adepts) who have attained the grace of nandin,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;n^an^dhikaL n^Alvar chivayOka mAmuni&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The 4 nandins, and then the muni shivayogI,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;manRU thozudha padhanychali viyAkramar&lt;br&gt;&#xA;pata~njali of the holy temple and vyAghrapAda,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The akShara puruSha maNDala of the pUrva srotas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-07-14_the-akshara-purusha-mandala-of-the-purva-srotas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-07-14_the-akshara-purusha-mandala-of-the-purva-srotas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/1600/shiva_puruSha.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/320/shiva_puruSha.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/320/shiva_puruSha.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The five faced one manifests as the inactive matter at the origin, the&#xA;all-pervading matter in the universe and the vaccuum from which all&#xA;emerges. Hence is worshipped as:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;shAntAya namaH | sarvagatAya namaH | shUnyAya namaH |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;These three states of the deva are stationed in the akShara puruSha&#xA;maNDala. The five short vowels are the faces and the 7 long vowels are&#xA;the limbs of the body. They are conjoined with the nasal bindu. The&#xA;visarga is the mighty astra, the trishUla of tatpuruSha. All this is&#xA;shiva and the core is his mahAmantra hauM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The heart of the tantra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2005-03-11_the-heart-of-the-tantra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2005-03-11_the-heart-of-the-tantra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The very word tantra conveys that deep meaning to the “knowers”. That&#xA;secret power that resides in the ‘hR^idaya‘ of bhairava and is known as&#xA;kaulinI. The anuttara of its own confers kaulika perfection. The tantra&#xA;is like a science because it is reproducible in its real form. The&#xA;sAdhaka on the true path first gets a glimpse of “kaulika existence”&#xA;when he can grasp the the samvAda of manthAna bhairava and tripura&#xA;bhairavI. If he can go beyond, the bIja mantra activates the apparatus&#xA;of the chakras and the ever-sleeping kubjikA awakens and courses on the&#xA;“path”. The sAdhaka then experiences the awe as he realizes the&#xA;enfolded state of the vishva in the ‘hR^idaya‘. If the sAdhAka can go&#xA;beyond, then he is stationed at the the “mid-point”. There he sees the&#xA;oscillation of visarga moving in the two directions at once. When he&#xA;reaches there he has reproduced in totality the words of manthAna&#xA;bhairava. He reproduces the experience of the guru, he reproduces the&#xA;experience of the true tantrics of yore. This act of reproducing the&#xA;experience gives the sadhAka the experience of ecstasy. This is like the&#xA;feeling of doing real science the reproducibility of the observation/&#xA;the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The matta-mayUra vaMsha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-12-10_the-matta-mayura-vamsha-of-mantra-marga-siddhantin-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-12-10_the-matta-mayura-vamsha-of-mantra-marga-siddhantin-s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;लेखकः - &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;मनसतरङ्गिणीकारः&lt;/a&gt;।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An important, but neglected aspect of the history of India before the&#xA;cataclysmic Islamic interruption, was the role played by the&#xA;mantra-mArga siddhAnta shaiva-s in the unification of the country. We&#xA;had earlier spoken of our historical clansman, the great&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/06/varmashiva.html&#34;&gt;varmashiva&lt;/a&gt; of&#xA;vodAmayUtA, who converted to this lineage of shaiva-s and had&#xA;considerable influence with the royal patron of his age. But this just&#xA;one point in the broader scheme of things. A truly influential but now&#xA;forgotten branch of these shaiva-s was the branch of matta-mayUra, whose&#xA;history now can only be reconstructed from various scraps of information&#xA;such as the numerous inscriptions from various parts of India. The idea&#xA;here is not to enter into a detailed discussion of the controversial and&#xA;investigative aspects of this history – to be frank my own studies on&#xA;the matter are currently slow-moving due to preoccupation with&#xA;interesting problems in other areas of research. We simply present a few&#xA;of note here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mythology of tirumUlar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-08-25_the-mythology-of-tirumular/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-08-25_the-mythology-of-tirumular/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is clear from tirumantiram verses 337 onwards that tirumUlar was an&#xA;extreme sectarian shaiva. He cites several elements of shaiva mythology,&#xA;where the aim is plainly to show the supremacy of shiva over other gods.&#xA;He also sees a sadashiva higher than rudra in his world view, which is&#xA;typical of this stream of thought and the sectarian shAktas further go&#xA;on to subsume the five brahma, viShNu, rudra, mahesha and sadAshiva as&#xA;the 5 pretas forming the cot of the transfunctional shaktI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The pa~ncha vaktra chakra of the pUrva srotas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-07-13_the-pancha-vaktra-chakra-of-the-purva-srotas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-07-13_the-pancha-vaktra-chakra-of-the-purva-srotas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/1600/shiva.0.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/320/shiva.0.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/blogger/2010/410/320/shiva.0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pUrva srotas of the tantras of rudra is comprised of the garuDa&#xA;tantras, which encompass the glorious prANeshvarI and mR^ityu~njaya&#xA;vidyAs. However, less known are the aspects of the regular worship of&#xA;mahAdeva in this srotas. The most critical aspect of this the invocation&#xA;of the five-fold shiva through the pa~chavaktra chakra. AdhAra of the&#xA;worship is viShNu, who shall be first invoked with the formula :&lt;br&gt;&#xA;oM bhUr viShNave AdibhUtAya sarvAdhArAya mUrtaye svAhA ||&lt;br&gt;&#xA;He is offered an oblation in the fire or a pouring of water.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The primary tantras of rudra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2005-03-26_the-primary-tantras-of-rudra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2005-03-26_the-primary-tantras-of-rudra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;urdhvasrotas- siddhAnta tantras&lt;br&gt;&#xA;shivAgamas:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;1) kAmika 2) yogaja 3) chintya 4) kAraNa 5) ajita 6) dIpta 7) sUkShma&#xA;8) sahasraka 9) amshumAn and 10) suprabheda.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;rudrAgmas:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;11) vijaya 12) nihshvAsa 13) svAyambhuva 14) anala 15) vIrabhadra 16)&#xA;raurava 17) makuTa 18) vimala 19) chandraGNYAna 20) mukhabimba 21)&#xA;udgita 22) lalita 23) siddha 24) santAna 25) nArasiMha 26) pArameshvara&#xA;27) kiraNa 28) vAtUla&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Some auxilliary texts: 1) mata~Nga pArameshvara 2) mR^igendra 3)&#xA;parAkhya 4) upasvAyambhuva 5) aindram 6) mahAghoraM&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The trayodashi rite of the kaTha dIkShita-s</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-08-15_the-trayodashi-rite-of-the-katha-dikshita-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-08-15_the-trayodashi-rite-of-the-katha-dikshita-s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is courtesy of Rajita, whom the deva-s have given me the&#xA;fortune to know. I have only worked [partially] on akShara-shuddhi of&#xA;the mantra readings and put it together here with due permission.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The kaTha dIkShita-s who were shrauta ritualists as well as well&#xA;accomplished tantrics had a distinctive pradoShaM rite on the trayodashi&#xA;before mahAshivarAtrI and that is described here. Interestingly they&#xA;observed fast on trayodashi during the day time. The rite involves the&#xA;worship of baTuka bhairava, paramashiva, sadashiva and his parivAra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The unmatta bhairava tantraM of the saMmohana tradition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-11-11_the-unmatta-bhairava-tantram-of-the-sammohana-tradition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/2006-11-11_the-unmatta-bhairava-tantram-of-the-sammohana-tradition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mada-sagara-tumburu-and-the-4-devi-s&#34;&gt;mada-sAgara, tumburu and the 4 devI-s&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;dAnavendra realized that if he could get hold of the amR^ita of the&#xA;deva-s he would be victorious. For this he went over to the circle of&#xA;mAtR^ikA-s headed by chakrakarAlinI and invoked them to fight on his&#xA;side. He also got the anantavIra-s who had emanated from the 8 bhairavas&#xA;starting from asitA~Nga to kapAla to fight on his side. As a result the&#xA;mAtR^ikA’s and vIra-s attacked the deva-s and the great bhairava, and&#xA;while they were fighting dAnavendra stole their soma. He started to&#xA;dance victoriously and the devas and bhairava seeing their shakti-s and&#xA;vIra-s turn against them were stupefied. Then chakrakarAlinI and the&#xA;mAtR^ikA-s rushed to eat up the deva-s and bhairava. As they were&#xA;opening their mouths and sticking out their tongues, rudra tried to save&#xA;the situation. He created a mada-sAgara. He then emanated a 4-petalled&#xA;lotus into that madasAgara. On the 4 petals sat the 4 devI-s jayA,&#xA;vijayA, ajitA and aparAjitA, and in the middle sat the terrifying 4&#xA;faced emanation of mahAdeva-&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/02/tumburu-manifestation-of-rudra.html&#34;&gt;tumburu&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;They played melodiously on their vINas and captivated the mAtR^ikA-s and&#xA;held them spell bound. When they were thus de-activated, the deva-s and&#xA;tumburu attacked dAnavendra and killed him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>trika-siddhAnta-tension</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/trika-siddhAnta-tension/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/trika-siddhAnta-tension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1486211029000462342?t=GnmDmxOelM0Vt8i0Ba0cNQ&amp;amp;s=19&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the perspective of an outsider, I would say this tension goes back to mahAdeva himself, who, as the bahUrupI R^ik, says manifests as aghora, ghora and ghoratara rudra-s. This tension was why the shaiva mantrashAstra became the triumphant metaphor in the Indosphere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;saiddhantika-aspects&#34;&gt;saiddhAntika aspects&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As an an adherent of the older vaidika tradition, specifically in its central aindra manifestation, I appreciate 2 key aspects of the saiddhAntika-s:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;their respect for the shruti &amp;amp; performance of rituals ordained by it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;their concern for social stability &amp;amp; striving for the same.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the centralized organization of the saiddhAntika tradition, while very good at maintaining religious aesthetics &amp;amp; scholarship (especially in vaiSheshika &amp;amp; nyAya) when the going is good was not as well equipped as the vaidika tradition in weathering the Abrahamistic predation in H civilization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>upaniShat-antiquity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/upaniShat-antiquity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/upaniShat-antiquity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1703968667778556045&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This +++(=gaNapaty-atharvashIrSham)+++ and a related text the varadopaniShat are late texts. How late is hard to pinpoint. As I&amp;rsquo;ve pointed out before, the singular vinAyaka is a late-coalescing deity. This upaniShat &amp;amp; varada describe the mUlamantra (gaM) &amp;amp; the famed gaNapati-rakShohA mantra.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Sino-Nipponic transmission of these mantra-s suggests that they were popular by 860 CE. However, we don&amp;rsquo;t find evidence for gANapatya tradition at the beginning of the common era.  So that gives you an approximate timeline for the emergence of these traditions related to these mantra-s. The South Indian V1s have secondarily added vedic accents to it in the late medieval period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wood</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/wood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dagens tried to identify as many of the trees as possible among those listed in two shaiva sthApanA-tantra-s. The Sanskrit name along with his ID &amp;amp; the images or parts of a temple made from them is given. While in some cases I&amp;rsquo;m doubtful, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure the alternative is better. A corollary to this is that temples and the images in them were made from wood for a long time. We don&amp;rsquo;t have any historical exemplars of such surviving due to the marUnmatta-s &amp;amp; natural causes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>yavana shaiva</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/yavana-shaiva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/yavana-shaiva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are well aware of the yavana vaiShNava from the Heliodorus inscription. But where there yavana shaiva? The case of lakulIsha points to this being the case. This unusual 1 foot head of rudra from Mathura might be take as evidence. It is unlike any other depiction of rudra from Mathura or elsewhere from 200BCE-200 ACE. If it represented a stand form as in some of the early images it must have been upto 6 feet. We posit that it was made by a yavana shaiva following the conventions of his own iconography.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>पाताल-रुद्राः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/pAtAla-rudrAH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/MT/pAtAla-rudrAH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1777928120282046668&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1777935070893891902&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are multiple pAtAla-rudra-s but hATakesha is the ultimate one of them.In shaiva mantramArga, the rudra presiding over the 7th netherworld sauvarNa is hATakeshvara. His place is said to be inhabited by gaNa-s, rudra-s &amp;amp; their consort, the bhaginI-s (the goddesses of the vAma srotas), mAtR^i-s. Peculiarly the svachChanda account distinguishes the yoginI-s from the yogakanyA-s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;kShemarAja tries to interpret them as human yoginI-s who have acquired siddhi-s through sAdhana and directly at birth, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
