<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Woodroffe on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Woodroffe on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>००</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/00/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction-and-preface&#34;&gt;Introduction and Preface&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PREFACE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE Indian Tantras, which are numerous, constitute the Scripture (&lt;em&gt;Shastra&lt;/em&gt;) of the Kaliyuga, and as such are the voluminous source of present and practical orthodox &amp;ldquo;Hinduism.&amp;rdquo; The Tantra Shastra is, in fact, and whatever be its historical origin, a development of the &lt;em&gt;Vaidika Karmakanda&lt;/em&gt;, promulgated to meet the needs of that age. Shiva says: &amp;ldquo;For the benefit of men of the Kali age, men bereft of energy and dependent for existence on the food they eat, the Kaula doctrine,&#xA;O auspicious one! is given&amp;rdquo; (Chap. IX., verse 12). To the Tantra we must therefore look if we would understand aright both ritual, &lt;em&gt;yoga&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;sadhana&lt;/em&gt; of all kinds, as also the general principles of which these practices are but the objective expression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०१</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-1----questions-relating-to-the-liberation-of-beings&#34;&gt;Chapter 1  - Questions relating to the Liberation of Beings&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE enchanting summit of the Lord of Mountains, resplendent with all its various jewels, clad with many a tree and many a creeper, melodious with the song of many a bird, scented with the fragrance of all the season’s flowers, most beautiful, fanned by soft, cool, and perfumed breezes, shadowed by the still shade of stately trees; where cool groves resound with the sweet-voiced songs of troops of Apsara, and in the forest depths flocks of kokila maddened with passion sing; where (Spring) Lord of the Seasons with his followers ever abide (the Lord of Mountains, Kailasa); peopled by (troops of) Siddha, Charana, Gandharva, and Ganapatya (1-5). It was there that Parvati, finding Shiva, Her gracious Lord, in mood serene, with obeisance bent low and for the benefit of all the worlds questioned Him, the Silent Deva, Lord of all things movable and immovable, the ever Beneficent and ever Blissful One, the nectar of Whose mercy abounds as a great ocean, Whose very essence is the Pure Sattva Guna, He Who is white as camphor and the Jasmine flower, the Omnipresent One, Whose raiment is space itself, Lord of the poor and the beloved Master of all yogi, Whose coiled and matted hair is wet with the spray of Ganga and (of Whose naked body) ashes are the adornment only; the passionless One, Whose neck is garlanded with snakes and skulls of men, the three-eyed One, Lord of the three worlds, with one hand wielding the trident and with the other bestowing blessings; easily appeased, Whose very substance is unconditioned Knowledge; the Bestower of eternal emancipation, the Ever-existent, Fearless, Changeless, Stainless, One without defect, the Benefactor of all, and the Deva of all Devas (5-10).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०२</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-2----introduction-to-the-worship-of-brahman&#34;&gt;Chapter 2  - Introduction to the Worship of Brahman&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HAVING heard the words of the Devi, Shangkara, Bestower of happiness on the world, great Ocean of mercy, thus of the truth of things spoke.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sadashiva said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O Exalted and Holy One! Benefactress of the universe, well has it been asked by Thee. By none has such an auspicious question been asked aforetime (2). Worthy of all thanks art Thou, Who knoweth all good, Benefactress of all born in this age, O Gentle One! Thou art Omniscient. Thou knowest the past, present, and future, and Dharmma. What Thou hast said about the past, present, and future, and, indeed, all things, is in accordance with Dharmma, and is the truth, and is without a doubt accepted by Me. O Sureshvari! I say unto you most truly and without all doubt that men, whether they be of the twice born or other castes, afflicted as they are by this sinful Age, and unable to distinguish the pure from the impure, will not obtain purity or the success of their desired ends by the Vedic ritual, or that prescribed by the Sanghitas and Smritis (3-6). Verily, verily, and yet again verily, I say unto you that in this Age there is no way to liberation but that proclaimed by the Agama (7). I, O Blissful One, have already foretold in the Vedas, Smritis, and Puranas,&amp;rsquo; that in this Age the wise shall worship after the doctrine of the Agama (8). Verily, verily, and beyond all doubt, I say to you that there is no liberation for him who in this Age, heedless of such doctrine, follows another (9). There is no Lord but I in this world, and I alone am He Who is spoken of in the Vedas, Puranas, and Smritis and Sanghitas (10). The Vedas and the Puranas proclaim Me to be the cause of the purity of the three worlds, and they who are averse to My doctrine are unbelievers and sinners, as great as those who slay a Brahmana (11). Therefore, O Devi! the worship of him who heeds not My precepts is fruitless, and, moreover, such an one goes to hell (12). The fool who would follow other doctrine heedless of Mine is as great a sinner as the slayer of a Brahmana or of a woman, or a parricide; have no doubt of that (13).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०३</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-3----description-of-the-worship-of-the-supreme-brahman&#34;&gt;Chapter 3  - Description of the Worship of the Supreme Brahman&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SHRI DEVI said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O Deva of the Devas, great Deva, Guru of Brihaspati himself, Thou Who discourseth of all Scriptures, Mantra, Sadhana, and hast spoken of the Supreme Brahman by the adoration of Whom mortals attain happiness and liberation, do Thou,&#xA;O Lord! deign to instruct us in the way of service of the Supreme Soul and of the observances, Mantra, and meditation in His worship. It is my desire,&#xA;O Lord! to hear the essential substance of all these from Thee (1-4).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०४</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-4----introduction-of-the-worship-of-the-supreme-prakriti&#34;&gt;Chapter 4  - Introduction of the Worship of the Supreme Prakriti&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HAVING listened with attention to that which has been said concerning the worship of the Supreme Brahman, the Supreme Devi greatly pleased again thus questioned Shankara (1).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shri Devi said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O Lord of the Universe and Husband! I bathe with contentment in the nectar of Thy words concerning the excellent worship of the Supreme, which lead to the well-being of the world and to the path of Brahman, and gives light, intelligence, strength, and prosperity (2-3). Thou hast said, 0 Ocean of Mercy! that as union with the Brahman is attainable through worship of Him, so, it may be attained by worship of Me (4). I wish to know, O Lord! of this excellent worship of Myself, which as Thou sayest is the cause of union of the worshipper with the Brahman (5). What are its rites, and by what means may it be accomplished? What is its Mantra, and what the form of its meditation and mode of worship? (6). O Shambhu! who but Thee, great Physician of earthly ills, is fit to speak of it, from its beginning to its end, and in all its detail agreeable as it is to Me and beneficent to all humanity? (7).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०५</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-5----the-formation-of-the-mantras-placing-of-the-jar-and-purification-of-the-elements-of-worship&#34;&gt;Chapter 5  - The Formation of the Mantras, Placing of the Jar, and Purification of the Elements of Worship&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SHRI SADASHIVA said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thou art the Adya Parama Shakti, Thou art all Power. It is by Thy power that We (the Trinity) are powerful in the acts of creation, preservation, and destruction. Endless and of varied colour and form are Thy appearances, and various are the strenuous efforts whereby the worshippers may realize them. Who can describe them? (1-2). In the Kula Tantras and Agamas I have, by the aid of but a small part of Thy mercies and with all My powers, described the Sadhana and Archana of Thy appearances; yet nowhere else is this very secret Sadhana revealed. It is by the grace of this (Sadhana), O Blessed One! that Thy mercy in Me is so great (3-4). Questioned by Thee I am no longer able to conceal it. For Thy pleasure, O Beloved! I shall speak of that which is dearer to Me than even life itself (5). To all sufferings it brings relief. It wards off all dangers. It gives Thee pleasure, and is the way by which Thou art most swiftly obtained (6). For men rendered wretched by the taint of the Kali Age, short-lived and unfit for strenuous effort, this is the greatest wealth (7). In this (sadhana) there is no need for a multiplicity of Nyasa, for fasting or other practices of self-restraint. It is simple and pleasurable, yet yields great fruit to the worshipper (8). Then first listen, O Devi! to the Mantroddhara of the Mantra, the mere hearing of which liberates man from future births while yet living (9).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०६</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-6----placing-of-the-shri-patra-homa-formation-of-the-chakra-and-other-rites&#34;&gt;Chapter 6  - Placing of the Shri-patra, Homa, Formation of the Chakra, and other Rites&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SHRI DEVI said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As Thou hast kindness for Me, pray tell Me, O Lord! more particularly about the Pancha-tattvas and the other observances of which Thou hast spoken (1).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shri Sadashiva said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are three kinds of wine which are excellent – namely, that which is made from molasses, rice, or the Madhuka flower. There are also various other kinds made from the juice of the palmyra and date tree, and known by various names according to their substance and place of production. They are all declared to be equally appropriate in the worship of the Devata (2).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०७</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-7-----hymn-of-praise-stotra-amulet-kavacha-and-the-description-of-the-kula-tattva&#34;&gt;Chapter 7  -  Hymn of Praise (Stotra), Amulet (Kavacha), and the description of the Kula-tattva&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PARVATI was pleased at hearing the revelation of the auspicious Mantra of the Adya Kalika, which yields abundant blessings, is the only means of attaining to a knowledge of the Divine essence, and leads to liberation; as also at hearing of the morning rites, the rules relating to bathing, Sandhya, the purification of Bhang, the methods of external and internal Nyasa and worship, the sacrifice of animals, Homa, the formation of the circle of worship, and the partaking of the holy food. Bowing low with modesty, the Devi questioned Shankara (1-3).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०८</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-8----the-dharmma-and-customs-of-the-castes-and-ashramas&#34;&gt;Chapter 8  - The Dharmma and Customs of the Castes and Ashramas&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AFTER hearing of the various forms of Dharmma, Bhavani, Mother of the worlds, Destructress of all worldly bonds, spoke again to Shankara (1).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shri Devi said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have heard of the different Dharmma, which bring happiness in this world and the next, and bestow piety, wealth, fulfilment of desire, ward off danger, and are the cause of union with the Supreme (2). I wish now to hear of the castes and of the stages of life. Speak in Thy kindness, O Omnipresent One! of these, and of the mode of life which should be observed therein (3).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०९</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-9----the-ten-kinds-of-purificatory-rites-sangskara&#34;&gt;Chapter 9  - The Ten Kinds of Purificatory Rites (Sangskara)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE Adorable Sadashiva said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O Virtuous One! I have spoken to Thee of the custom and religious duties appropriate to the different castes and stages of life. Do thou now listen whilst I tell Thee of the purificatory rites of the different castes (1). Without such rites, O Devi! the body is not purified, and he who is not purified may not perform the ceremonies relating to the Devas and the Pitris (2). Therefore it is that men of every caste, commencing with the Vipras, who desire their welfare in this life and hereafter, should, in all things and with care, perform the purificatory rites which have been ordained for their respective castes (3).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>१०</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-10---rites-relating-to-vriddhi-shraddha-funeral-rites-and-purnabhisheka&#34;&gt;Chapter 10 - Rites relating to Vriddhi Shraddha, Funeral Rites, and Purnabhisheka&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SHRI DEVI said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have now learned from Thee, O Lord! of the ordinances relating to Kushandika and the ten Sang-skaras. Do Thou now,O&#xA;Deva! reveal to Me the ordinances relating to Briddhi Shraddha (1). O Shangkara! tell Me in detail, both for My pleasure and the benefit of all beings, in which of the sacramental and dedicatory ceremonies Kushandika and Briddhi Shraddha should be, or be not, performed. Say this, O Maheshana (2-3).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>११</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-11----the-account-of-expiatory-rites&#34;&gt;Chapter 11 -  The Account of Expiatory Rites&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LISTENING to the injunctions of Shambhu relating to the different castes and stages of life, Aparna was greatly pleased, and questioned Shangkara thus (1):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shri Devi said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thou hast, O Lord! out of Thy kindness for Me and in Thy omniscience, spoken of the customs and the rules of religious conduct and sacraments for the well-being of the world (2). But the men of the Kali Age, being wicked, and blinded by anger and lust, atheists, of wavering minds and addicted to the gratification of their senses, will not in their ignorance and folly follow the way laid down by Thee; it behoves Thee, O Ishana! to say what will be the means of their liberation (3-4).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>१२</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-12---an-account-of-the-eternal-and-immutable-dharmma&#34;&gt;Chapter 12 - An Account of the Eternal and Immutable Dharmma&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SHRI SADASHIVA said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O Primordial One! I am speaking to Thee again of the everlasting laws; the wise King may easily rule his subjects if he follows them (1).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If Kings did not establish rules, men in their covetousness would quarrel among themselves, even with their friends, relatives, and their superiors (2).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These self-seeking men, O Devi! would for the sake of wealth kill one another, and be full of sin by reason of their maliciousness and desire to thieve (3).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>१३</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-13---installation-of-the-devata&#34;&gt;Chapter 13 - Installation of the Devata&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PARVATI, the Mother of the three worlds, Her mind engrossed with thoughts for the purification of men polluted with the impurities of the Kali Age, humbly asked Mahesha, the Deva among Devas, who had thus spoken of the essence of all the Nigamas, which is the seed of heaven and final liberation (as follows) (1):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shri Devi said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How should the form of Mahakali be thought of, She who is the Great Cause, the Primordial Energy, the Great Effulgence, more subtle than the subtlest elements? (2).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>१४</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/AgamaH/mahA-nirvAna-tantram/woodroffe/14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-14---the-consecration-of-shiva-linga-and-description-of-the-four-classes-of-avadhutas&#34;&gt;Chapter 14 - The Consecration of Shiva-linga and Description of the Four Classes of Avadhutas&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SHRI DEVI said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am grateful to Thee, O Lord of Mercy! in that Thou hast in Thy discourse upon the Worship of the Adya Shakti, spoken, in Thy mercy, of the mode of Worship of various other Devas (1).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thou hast spoken of the Installation of a Movable Shiva-linga, but what is the object of installing an immovable Shiva-linga, and what are the rites relating to the installation of such a Linga? (2).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
