<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/kAlAmukhAH/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/kAlAmukhAH/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>kAlAmukhas-II</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/kAlAmukhAH/articles/MT/2005-03-23_kalamukhas-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/kAlAmukhAH/articles/MT/2005-03-23_kalamukhas-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Modern historians have seen the vIrashaivas as an organic evolute of the&#xA;kAlAmukhas. While their attachment to li~Nga worship, shiva devotion&#xA;and monastic organization are indeed comparable, there are many&#xA;differences. The vIrashaiva cult, while found by a brahmin basava, had a&#xA;rather anti-brahminical streak. Firstly, it was vociferously critical of&#xA;the varNAshrama dharma and secondly sought to replace brahminical rites&#xA;with imitations. For example, they used the rudra gAyatrI in place of&#xA;the savitA gAyatrI for the saMdhya rite. The virashaiva cult, as&#xA;characterized by the vachanas of basava, was low on philosophy and high&#xA;on rhetoric, and associated, as per its own admission, with murder of&#xA;the ruling king, religious persecution and raising of private militias.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The kAlAmukhas-I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/kAlAmukhAH/articles/MT/2005-02-23_the-kalamukhas-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/kAlAmukhAH/articles/MT/2005-02-23_the-kalamukhas-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most enigmatic of the shaiva groups of India were the&#xA;kAlAmukhas. Their origins and the rise to power are shrouded in mystery.&#xA;An added mystery is their suddence disappearance despite their prominent&#xA;presence in the mideaval period. I stood before a great shrine of The&#xA;god once built by the kAlAmukhas in the city of my birth and wondered&#xA;about their origins. They were described as kAlAmukhas after the&#xA;practice of marking their foreheads with a black streak. There were two&#xA;great schools or councils (pariShads) kAlAmukhas. The siMha pariShad was&#xA;common in Andhra and the shakti pariShad was common in Karnataka. The&#xA;latter pariShad is most actively represented in epigraphic records&#xA;studied by Lorenzen. Though there is not much evidence for the&#xA;kAlAmukhas having any presence elsewhere in India, the South Indian&#xA;epigraphic records suggest that they were also present in Kashmir. We do&#xA;not find much connection between the kAlAmukhas and the much maligned&#xA;kApAlikas, and the siddhAnta shaiva streams. The main center of the&#xA;shakti parishad was the dakShiNa kedAreshvara temple in North Karnataka&#xA;from where the kAlAmukhas fanned out into the rest of the state. From&#xA;the inscriptions we get the following lineage of the kAlAmukhas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
