<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 Early Śaivism on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/1_Early_shaivism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 Early Śaivism on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/1_Early_shaivism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 From Mantramārga Back to Atimārga:</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/1_Early_shaivism/1_From_mantramArga_Back_to_atimArga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/1_Early_shaivism/1_From_mantramArga_Back_to_atimArga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Atimārga as a Self-referential Term&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Peter C. Bisschop&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The impact of Alexis Sanderson’s scholarship can be easily measured by the subject of the present paper. Before 1988, when Sanderson published his groundbreaking article “Śaivism and the Tantric Traditions,” the term Atimārga was hardly used by anyone with the exception of a few specialists of Tantric Śaivism, and it certainly was never addressed systematically.1 Thus, for exam ple, Minoru Hara, who completed his dissertation on the Pāśupatas at Harvard in 1966 and published extensively on the Pāśupata tradition in the subsequent decades, never once used the term.2 In the years to come, however, various scholars started to use it with great confidence in increasing numbers and cur rently the Atimārga is widely regarded as one of the two major divisions of Śaivism, alongside that of the Mantramārga. Quite influential in the dissem ination of the term has been Gavin Flood, who adopted it in his An Intro duction to Hinduism (1996). The chapters on the Śaiva and Śākta traditions in this book are deeply dependent on Sanderson’s scholarship. As an illustration of how commonplace and accepted its use has become, reference may also be made to the entry on Atimārga in the popular A Dictionary of Hinduism by W.J. Johnson (2009). The description clearly reflects Sanderson’s scholar ship:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Why Are the Skull-Bearers (Kāpālikas) Called Soma?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/1_Early_shaivism/2_Why_Are_the_Skull-Bearers_kApAlikas_Called_Soma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/1_Early_shaivism/2_Why_Are_the_Skull-Bearers_kApAlikas_Called_Soma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Judit Törzsök&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 The Question&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Kāpālikas or Skull-Bearers, who formed the third group of the Atimārga, alongside the Pāśupatas and the Lākulas,1 were perhaps the most notorious Śaiva ascetics of classical India. They were known for their cremation ground rituals and for wandering around with a skull for an alms bowl. The skull (kapāla), their most conspicuous attribute, also provided their name. But the Kāpālikas are also designated as Somasiddhāntins, “Those of the Soma Doc trine,”2 or the “Soma People with the Skull.”3 These appellations seem to have been of some importance because their initiation names also included or ended in -soma in most cases (e.g. Satyasoma, Devasomā,4 Somibhaṭṭāraka5). What was this Somasiddhānta, doctrine of Soma or teaching about (the) Soma?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Dressing for Power</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/1_Early_shaivism/3_Dressing_for_Power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/1_Early_shaivism/3_Dressing_for_Power/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dressing for Power: On vrata, caryā, and vidyāvrata in the Early Mantramārga, and on the Structure of the Guhyasūtra of the Niśvāsatattvasaṃhitā&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dominic Goodall&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If, twenty years ago, you had read most of the literature published before the 1990s about the Śaivasiddhānta, you would probably have received the impres sion that this was primarily a South Indian movement, whose scriptures, called āgamas, were divided into four sections, or pādas, devoted to ritual (kriyā), doctrine ( jñāna), yoga and pious conduct (caryā). The first two of these four sections, the kriyā-pāda and the jñāna-pāda, you would have learnt, were the most important, the kriyāpāda being devoted to describing the rituals practised in the Śaiva temples of the Tamil-speaking area, and the jñānapāda (or vidyā pāda) being devoted to teaching and defending a strictly dualist system that presents an ontological ladder of thirty-six tattvas, but that recognises three irreducible ontological categories: pati, paśu and pāśa. That is to say: the Lord (pati), bound souls (paśu), and the bonds that bind them (pāśa), namely Mat ter, karman and an innate impurity called mala or āṇava-mala.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
