<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 Religion, the State, and Social History on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/3_Religion_the_State_and_Social_History/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 Religion, the State, and Social History on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/3_Religion_the_State_and_Social_History/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>10 Buddhism, Kingship and the Protection of the State: The Suvarṇaprabhāsottamasūtra and Dhāraṇī Literature</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/3_Religion_the_State_and_Social_History/10_Buddhism_Kingship_and_the_Protection_of_the_Sta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/3_Religion_the_State_and_Social_History/10_Buddhism_Kingship_and_the_Protection_of_the_Sta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gergely Hidas&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article focuses first on the ritual core of the Suvarṇaprabhāsottamasūtra, which teaches the protection of the state for the mutual benefit of the Bud dhist Sangha and the monarch. The essay then explores the ways in which this theme appears in dhāraṇī literature in the first half of the first millennium.1 It is shown that offering safeguard to rulers and their regions is a long-established practice in South Asian Buddhism, persisting into modern times, and that there have been a variety of incantation scriptures available for accomplishing this task.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Adapting Śaiva Tantric Initiation for Exoteric Circles: The Lokadharmiṇī Dīkṣā and Its History in Early Medieval Sources</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/3_Religion_the_State_and_Social_History/11_Adapting_shaiva_Tantric_Initiation_for_Exoteric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/3_Religion_the_State_and_Social_History/11_Adapting_shaiva_Tantric_Initiation_for_Exoteric/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nina Mirnig&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A consistent concern in the study of early Śaivism is to understand the scope of the clientele texts were written for, and how representative this literature was of practices on the ground at given times. The methodological limita tions we face in exploring this largely prescriptive body of literature in relation to actual practice are notorious. Yet, in his seminal works on Śaiva religious history, Alexis Sanderson developed groundbreaking insights into the socio religious and political landscape in which the surviving texts were produced, reconstructing processes that led to the dominant position of Śaivism in the medieval Indic world. Thanks to his pioneering research, and that of other scholarswho have taken up the subject in the wake of his work, our understand ing of the relative chronology of Śaiva scriptures and medieval authors has also greatly improved.1 This increasingly enables us to investigate these materials historically, and thus to pursue questions of a socio-historical nature, which are at the heart of Sanderson’s work. In his own words (Sanderson 2005, 230),&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Innovation and Social Change in the Vale of Kashmir, circa 900–1250 C E</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/3_Religion_the_State_and_Social_History/12_Innovation_and_Social_Change_in_the_Vale_of_Kas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/3_Religion_the_State_and_Social_History/12_Innovation_and_Social_Change_in_the_Vale_of_Kas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John Nemec&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;iti prakaṭito mayā sughaṭa eṣa mārgo navo mahāgurubhir ucyate sma śiva dṛṣṭiśāstre yathā |&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thus I have set forth this new (nava), easy path as it was explained by my distinguished teacher [Somānanda] in the śāstra, [entitled] the Śivadṛṣṭi. Īśvarapratyabhijñākārikās of Utpaladeva at 4.16ab&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;∵&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is well known that religious agents in premodern South Asia appealed to the purported timelessness and transcendence of their scriptural sources to secure not only their legitimacy but also that of the ideas found in them. Equally well known—in no small part due to the work of Alexis Sanderson on the social history of Śaiva and other religious traditions in early-medieval Kashmir and elsewhere—is the fact that premodern South Asian religions do not appear as unchanging and immobile traditions in social stasis. Quite the opposite: the various religious traditions of medieval South Asia were nothing if not inno vative in idea and practice, most notably in their literary productions. These myriad religious traditions, moreover, had a measurable and not insignificant influence on contemporaneous social life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Toward a History of the Navarātra, the Autumnal Festival of the Goddess</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/3_Religion_the_State_and_Social_History/13_Toward_a_History_of_the_navarAtra_the_Autumnal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/3_Religion_the_State_and_Social_History/13_Toward_a_History_of_the_navarAtra_the_Autumnal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bihani Sarkar&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this essay, I wish to address the problems a historian encounters while explaining the function and origin of ancient rituals. One is particularly con fronted by these problems when dealing with a ritual such as the Navarātra. With regard to its function, the festival resists sharp distinctions between the sacred and the temporal because it simultaneously propitiates a deity and sol emnizes the authority of a ruler. It seems to be two things at the same time: a rite of religious power and a rite of political power. In fact, in the South ern Navarātra, for instance as celebrated in Vijayanagara, the worship of the Goddess would take place largely out of view in a private shrine, while all the individual rites of the festival appeared to publicly celebrate a cult of the king in the larger communal area: the Navarātra thus appeared, as it did to Portuguese and Persian visitors to the Vijayanagara court, to be a political festival with a minor religious dimension.1 While explaining its origins, we run into even greater difficulty as the earliest traces of the Navarātra are found in more than one distinctive religious tradition: the Vaiṣṇava, the Śaiva, the Purāṇic and even possibly in regional traditions of communities outside mainstream ‘Hindu’ tra ditions. Where it truly “originates” is therefore difficult to see, though for clar ity’s sake I have proposed here that the Vaiṣṇava domain was where a mature, theologically coherent2 conception of the rite evolved. On the whole the ritual appears to have been of a composite character at each stage of its manifesta tion. The overall impression is that we are looking at many permutations of dif ferent rites with different origins that attached themselves around the central figure of the Goddess, and through her, and the demon-slaying mythologies sur rounding her, acquired a structural and thematic unity. In the following, I shall&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
