<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Sanderson on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/sanderson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Sanderson on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/sanderson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>shaiva-age</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/sanderson/shaiva-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/sanderson/shaiva-age/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(From GENESIS AND DEVELOPMENT OF TANTRISM&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Edited by&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Shingo EINOO )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Śaiva Age&lt;br&gt;&#xA;— The Rise and Dominance of Saivism During the Early Medieval Period —&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Alexis SANDERSON&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The early medieval period, from about the fifth century to the thirteenth, saw a decline in the role of Srauta sacrifice in the religious ceremonies under- ´ taken by Indian rulers. But it was not that kings turned aside from the brahman ical tradition in a fundamental sense. They continued to uphold the brahmanical social order of the castes and disciplines (varṇāśramadharmaḥ) and they were commonly commended in inscriptions from the fifth to the eighth centuries for having rigorously imposed it on their subjectṣWe see this in the case of the Maukhari Harivarman in the fifth century, the Maharājādhir āja Gopacandra of ¯ Vanga and the Parivr ˙ ajaka Mah ārāja Sam ¯ . kṣobha of D. abhalar ājya in the sixth, ¯ the Puṣyabhuti Prabh ākaravardhana of Kanyakubja, Bh āskaravarman of Pr āg- ¯ jyotiṣa, the Maitraka Kharagraha II Dharmaditya of Valabh ¯ī, the Gurjara Dadda ¯ III of Bharukaccha in the seventh, and the Licchavi Sivadeva of Nepal at the ´ turn of the seventh and eightḥ1 The same claim is seen in the account of the&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tAntric-traditions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/sanderson/tAntric-traditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/sanderson/tAntric-traditions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;36 Śaivism and the Tantric Traditions&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Alexis Sanderson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The term Saivism here refers to a number of distinct but historically related systems comprising theology, ritual, observance and yoga, which have been propagated in India as the teachings of the Hindu deity Siva. A Śaiva is one who practices such a system. To understand the term to mean &amp;lsquo;a worshipper of Śiva&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;one whose deity is Śiva&amp;rsquo; is less precise; for a Śaiva may well be a worshipper not of Śiva but of the Goddess (Devi). Though she is commonly represented as the consort of Śiva and, theologi- cally, as that god&amp;rsquo;s inherent power (śakti), it is none the less the defining mark of certain forms of Saivism that she is seen as transcending this marital and logical subordination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
