<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Summary on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Summary on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Tantrasāra begins by stating that perfect knowledge (pūrṇa-prathā) is the cause of liberation. It is the revelation of śiva-nature in one&amp;rsquo;s own Self. śiva, who by His power of freedom (svātantrya śakti) appears to be limited in knowledge and action, removes all veils by the same power.+++(5)+++ As a result of this, He shines in His pristine, self-refulgent, pure consciousness. On the dawn of supreme knowledge of the nature of light (prakāśa), marked by reflective self-knowledge (vimarśa), everything shines non-differently in the mirror of consciousness.+++(4)+++ While describing the nature of mokṣa, Abhinavagupta writes in the Paramārtha-sāra that there is no separate region of it, nor is one to proceed toward it, but it is to be realized by piercing the knots of ignorance by virtue of the full development of one&amp;rsquo;s own power of freedom. However, mokṣa should not be taken as the effect of knowledge (jñāna) and the latter the cause of it, but as the manifestation of the real nature of the Self (ātman).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second chapter begins with a brief presentation of anupāya. Anupāya is not counted under any upaya on account of its subtlety, and even more, because the person on whom the most intense descent of grace (śaktipāta) has fallen does not have any need for internal or external help in order to realize his identity with śiva. The word of the teacher, heard only once, places him on the transcendent path (anuttara-patha), the stable ground of the blissful nature of śakti, upon which he at once realizes the self-manifest Lord as his own very Self.+++(4)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ātman has the characteristics of light and freedom, and is free from all thought constructs (vikalpa). It is śiva, the absolute. It is without parts, the integral whole of infinite light that encompasses everything-the single realm of light where thought does not reach (nirvikalpaika-dhaman). Although an ordinary soul, in its contracted state as a result of the influence of the three impurities (malas), is not different from that light, it is unable to conceive this, and fails to realize its identity with that light. As soon as grace descends on it, even a little, he begins to realize the truth, and by a sudden flash, he is able to perceive that light without the intervention of any upaya.+++(4)+++ This perception is direct and immediate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The highest end for human beings is to attain the very nature of Parāmaśiva, who is ever free from determinacy or “thought constructs” (vikalpa). One is able to rid oneself of thought constructs by means of pure reasoning (sat-tarka), by listening to holy texts known as āgamas, and by following the teachings of a spiritual teacher. The practice of contemplating or viewing everything as the essential reality (śiva) is the means by which one is able to rise above impure thought constructs (aśuddha-vikalpas). The tantrasāra states that one considers oneself bound because of vikalpas. The wrong conception of one&amp;rsquo;s true nature as body, etc., is the cause of mundane existence; however, when a vikalpa of the opposite nature pure “thought construct&amp;quot; (śuddha-vikalpa) is born, it dispels the wrong kind of thought construct, places one on the right path, and enables one to attain the highest good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 आणव-प्रकाशनम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;thought-purificaiton&#34;&gt;Thought purificaiton&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When a thought construct (vikalpa) cannot become pure by itself, and one has to depend on other means for its purification, the aspirant is decidedly staying in the lower stage of spiritual development; in other words, in him śaktipāta has occurred to a lesser degree. Therefore, for the purification of vikalpas, and because he is limited himself, he resorts to means that are also limited. Hence, the individual takes up practices of the intellect (buddhi), vital energy (prāṇa), or the body itself for this purpose.+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter Six describes the method for the realization of essential reality by external means. In the preceding chapter, Abhinavagupta describes āṇavopāya, which helps the aspirant attain absorption into the divine Self through the means of uccāra, dhyāna, varṇa, and karaṇa. The present section discusses how a yogin adopts prāṇavāyu as the means for attaining his or her desired goal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From this chapter onward, whatever is described up to Chapter Twelve comes under the “formation of the place&amp;quot; (sthāna-prakalpana). The locations are three: the vital energy, the body, and other external objects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the seventh chapter, the text presents deśādhva, the path of space. It consists of objects of multifarious forms made manifest by the Lord by means of His power of activity. The form of any of these objects, such as house, courtyard, market, temple, garden, or forest, which are different from one another, shines to a limited subject only as being mutually distinct from one another, and also from the subject himself. To the Lord, who is perfect and there fore free from all limitations, all subjects and objects shine as his very Self. In reality, these forms have their substratum in pure consciousness, and so they shine nondifferently from it. In its free will, consciousness (saṁvid) veils its pure nature and manifests before the view of the limited subject as sūnya, prāṇa, and buddhi, and from this the embodied soul sees pictures of objects as distinct from the experiencing subject. Thus, sūnya, prāṇa, and buddhi shine externally as objects, but really they are not different from the Self.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the previous chapter we saw that worlds (bhuvanas) are the expansion of śakti, which keep all the multifarious forms of sub jects and their objects of experience within herself. Permeating them all is the highest universal, known as Parāmaśiva, who remains ever shining. That which is less pervasive than the high est universal, present in some bhuvanas but absent in others, is defined as a tattva; for example, solidity, firmness, and grossness are all qualities found in Brahmānda alone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This chapter classifies all the tattvas grouped under fifteen aspects as viewed by the seven kinds of knowing subjects: śiva, mantramaheśvara; mantreśvara, mantra, vijñānākala, pralaya kala, and sakala. These subjects each possess one of seven śaktis; thus counting the śaktis and the possessors of these śaktis, the number becomes fourteen. Including svarūpa, which refers to the &amp;ldquo;object in itself,&amp;rdquo; with these fourteen, each of the tattvas from prthvī to prakr̥ti has fifteen aspects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter Ten begins with a description of the general features of the subtle units constituting the manifested universe called kalās. Abhinavagupta defines a tattva as that which threads through all the worlds (bhuvanas), and kalā is that which invariably abides in the group of tattvas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The number of kalās are four, i.e., nivetti, pratisthā, vidyā, and śāntā. The four andas: pārthiva, prākrta, māyīya, and sāktā are made of these kalās.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This chapter discusses śaktipāta, but before giving a detailed account of it, the text deals with issues concerning the occurrence of the descent of grace in a particular individual. This has been dealt with in detail in our translation of the text and the additional: notes. The author presents and critiques three standard views regarding śaktipāta: (1) bondage, or saṁsāra, has ignorance as its root. When the rise of right knowledge occurs, the descent of grace also comes into being. This view has been refuted by the author. (2) Next, the view known as karmasāmya, that is, the bal ance of two opposing actions, is summarized. According to this theory, when karmasāmya occurs, śaktipāta is sure to take place. The author does not accept this view either. (3) The third view considers the ripening of mala (mala paripaka) as the cause of Śaktipāta, which is also rejected by the author.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this chapter, the author presents and substantiates the rea sons for the performance of initiations (diksā). In addressing the question of the necessity of dikṣā, the author states that initia tion alone is the means that leads the soul to enjoyment (bhoga) and finally helps one to attain liberation. Primarily, dikṣā sanc tifies the soul and produces in it the competency for receiving knowledge (jñāna), yoga, etc., for without obtaining dikṣā fol lowing the course of Śaiva Yoga would not be possible. Therefore dikṣā is considered to be the preliminary step in the progression from saṁskāra, to the proper practice of yoga, to perfection in&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here the author explains the necessity of and reasons for the ritual procedures that are to be performed on hilltops, river banks, and other holy spots. Though those places are considered to be auspi cious, they are really external, and thus of little help for attaining siddhis, in contrast to the internal seats (pithas), which are much more useful, because they concentrate the vital energy in differ ent locations in the body, and through this one is able to attain&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This chapter describes the procedure of initiation called putraka. On the third day after anointment, a mandala or diagram con sisting of three tridents with a lotus on each prong is drawn on the ground. All the rituals described in this chapter are to be performed in relation to it. Those groups of deities called the &amp;ldquo;external retinues&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;deities at the door&amp;rdquo; are worshipped outside. Then, in front of the mandala, moving from northeast to southeast, Ganesa, one&amp;rsquo;s teacher (guru), the teacher&amp;rsquo;s teacher (paramagurus), the lineage of previous teachers, the yoginis, the Goddess of Speech (Vāgiśvarī), and kṣetrapalas are worshipped. After receiving their permission, the teacher worships the nine paths (adhvas) in the tridents. On the middle prong of the middle most trident, the Goddess Srīparā and Bhairava are worshipped; the Goddess Śrīāparā is worshipped on the left, and the Goddess Śrīparāparā on the right. On the trident to the right, Srīparāparā is placed in the middle prong, while on the trident to the left Sriāparā is placed in the middle. Bhagavati is the supreme Goddess, and because of her presence everywhere, all activities become perfect,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This chapter describes the initiation given to a dying person. The recipient of such a dikṣā is a person who has been suffering from an incurable disease. The teacher, after making nyāsa of all the adhvas in him and purifying them one after the other, performs a nyāsa called marmakartani, by which he severs all the delicate&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;42 TANTRASĀRA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;joints and brings his consciousness to brahmarandhra. For the purpose of unification (yojana), he then offers the final oblation into the fire. Thus, the disciple becomes one with Parāmaśiva.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this chapter, the author describes the method of initiation that is given to those who are dead and who are not present during the procedure. For the purpose of bestowing it on the departed soul, the teacher brings nearby a device known as mahājāla prayoga, the application of a large net. To the person who is absent but not dead, this procedure is not followed..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This chapter gives the procedure known as lingoddhāra; it simply means “rescuing a person from a fallen state.&amp;quot; It is performed for one who has gone away from the right track by receiving initia tion from persons belonging to other systems, such as Vaisnava, Bauddha, and other lower Śaiva schools. However, the teacher will grant this type of initiation only when he becomes convinced that Śaktipāta has definitely occurred in a prospective disciple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this chapter the method of abhiseka is described. Abhiseka is given both to putraka and acārya types of disciples, provided they have received the sabīja form of initiation. The term sabīja means “with seed,&amp;quot; but it really signifies that this form of initiation is given to those who are competent enough to follow certain strict rules of conduct during their lifetime. On the other hand, the nir-bīja form of initiation is given to old and decrepit persons who are less assiduous and therefore unable to follow strict codes of conduct as enjoined by the holy text.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The funeral sacrifice is the final rite for every human being. Ini tiation is given during that period only to a person who, though he belonged to the highest Śaiva order, on account of some unknown factor lost the tradition and expired without performing the rites of atonement before death. Such a person is given initiation when his body is placed on the funeral pyre.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the purpose of rescuing the deceased, all the rituals are performed upon the body. The final offering into the fire (pūr nāhuti) is performed by burning the body. In order to convince ignorant people, the person who initiates causes the dead body to shake. He does this by means of kriyā, jñāna, and yoga, though it is not necessary for the release of the soul.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The present section discusses the disciple&amp;rsquo;s obligations, known as sesavartana, the duties that should be carried out until the end of his life. These duties are of three kinds: obligatory (nitya), occasional (naimittika), and kāmya, those performed for the fulfillment of some desire.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The nitya procedure is described in the following way: One should get up early in the morning and call to mind one&amp;rsquo;s desired deity first. After completing his essential activities, like wash ing, etc., and cleansing himself, he should take his seat facing north. He then purifies his body, the place where he sits, and his mind. Then he performs nyāsa upon the appropriate places with the mantra, followed by displaying an appropriate mudrā. Then he performs dhyāna in two ways: first, abiding in duality, and then in a mixed dual-nondual way. Next, mental worship of the deity is performed in the body, then in prāṇa, in the intellect, and finally in the void (vyoma). This is followed by japa, and finally the completed sequence of worship is offered to the deity. All this is to be performed every day, in every sandhya, for the purpose of achieving identification with the deity. Four sandhyas have been mentioned in Chapter Six. According to the author, through medi tation during sandhya, endless absorption (anantatanmayi bhāva) in the Supreme comes about, which.in turn gives birth to a lasting state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This chapter presents the authority of agamas. In the Tantrāloka, āgama has been defined as a well-known fact of old, as prasid dhi. It also emphasizes the point that even agreement and contra riety (anvaya and vyatireka), which are the very life of inference,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;46 TANTRASĀRA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;also depend on prasiddhi. Similarly, perception looks for prasid dhi as its support; for without its help, which is thought to be of the nature of self-reflection (svātmavimarśātmika prasiddhi), it would not be possible to consider anything as acceptable or avoid able. Therefore, prasiddhi lies at the root of every worldly transac tion. The great Lord, who is all-perfect, with the characteristic of I-consciousness, and who is omniscient, is the source of all pra siddhis. He, the Lord, is adorned with a multitude of prasiddhis with the form of enjoyment (bhoga) and release (apavarga).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/sampradAyaH/kaulaH_shAktaH/sampradAyaH/pUrvAmnAyaH_trikam/abhinavagupta-mUlam/tantrAlokaH/tantrasAraH/00/Summary/22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This last chapter explains the nature of Kulācara. It should be noted at the outset that this form of worship is not meant for every body, but is only for those who are well advanced, and in whom the inclination for performing such rituals has grown strong; only because of this are they entitled to perform this worship of the divine according to this method.+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When a person becomes free from determination (vikalpa) and is able to attain steadiness in the indeterminate state (nirvikalpa), only then is one entitled to worship according to kulakrama, for it is stated in the Tantrāloka that if, during the performance of this ritual, one thinks of the object of worship as different from himself, he fails to attain either siddhi or mukti. One who has plunged into the secret of this ritual and follows its course is really endowed with the highest knowledge. Therefore, Jayaratha writes in his commentary on Tantrāloka 29:102 that those great souls who are really free from vikalpas take up this course, as prescribed by the Kula system. Particularly, they follow the course only to see if their mind, in the presence of allurements, is truly steady in pure consciousness (samvidadvaite) or not.+++(5)+++ For this reason, they do not think it immoral to practice in the company of female partners (duti).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
