<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;5 Art and Architecture on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/5_Art_and_Architecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;5 Art and Architecture on आगमे शैवे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/5_Art_and_Architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>20 The Early Śaiva Maṭha: Form and Function</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/5_Art_and_Architecture/20_The_Early_shaiva_maTha_Form_and_Function/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/5_Art_and_Architecture/20_The_Early_shaiva_maTha_Form_and_Function/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Libbie Mills&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We should begin by determining what we think a maṭha to be in the early Śaiva context. In the seventh and eighth centuries, maṭhas began to receive royal patronage. By the ninth and tenth centuries maṭhas collected taxes and agri cultural profits (Sears 2014, 6). In the later period and in the south, maṭhas come to be a place for pilgrims passing through, or an institution for profes sional adepts, a place one might abide in on a hereditary basis. There is a rise in endowments for maṭhas in the eleventh and twelfth centuries, with the head of the maṭha perhaps being the rājaguru, the royal guru, of the dominion, hence a figure of political importance (Nandi 1987, 194–195).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Kriyāsaṃgrahapañjikā</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/5_Art_and_Architecture/21_kriyAsaMgrahapanjikA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/5_Art_and_Architecture/21_kriyAsaMgrahapanjikA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Kriyāsaṃgrahapañjikā of Kuladatta and its Parallels in the Śaiva Pratiṣṭhātantras&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ryugen Tanemura&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most people think that the prominent features of Tantric religions are their esoteric teachings. This might mislead us into supposing that these religions were limited to restricted communities. But in fact these religions extended over a much wider domain.We see this if we consider the fact that both Śaivism and Tantric Buddhism offered a wide range of public social rituals.1 Following&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Mañjuśrī as Ādibuddha: The Identity of an Eight armed Form of Mañjuśrī Found in Early Western Himalayan Buddhist Art in the Light of Three Nāmasaṃgīti-Related Texts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/5_Art_and_Architecture/22_manjushrI_as_Adibuddha_The_Identity_of_an_Eight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/5_Art_and_Architecture/22_manjushrI_as_Adibuddha_The_Identity_of_an_Eight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anthony Tribe&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article I suggest that an eight-armed Mañjuśrī found in early Western Himalayan Art be identified not as the bodhisattva Mañjuśrī but as the Ādibud dha.1 This figure is distinctive in that it holds four swords, one in each of its four right hands, andfour book volumes, one in each of itsfour left hands. Previously identified as a form of Dharmadhātuvāgīśvara Mañjuśrī,2 this image is found in three locations in the Western Himalayas. Two of these are in Ladakh: one at Alchi in the Sumtsek (Gsum-brtsegs, “Three-Storeyed”) Temple; the other at Mangyu, where there are two images, the first in the Two-armed Maitreya Chapel, the second in the Village Stūpa.3 These three images are murals. The third location is in Spiti, where there is a clay sculpture in the Golden Temple or Serkhang (Gser-khang) at Lalung.4&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Life and Afterlife of Sādṛśya: Revisiting the Citrasūtra through the Nationalism-Naturalism Debate in Indian Art History</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/5_Art_and_Architecture/23_Life_and_Afterlife_of_sAdRshya_Revisiting_the_c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH_shaivaH/meta/articles/shaivism_and_the_Tantric_Traditions/5_Art_and_Architecture/23_Life_and_Afterlife_of_sAdRshya_Revisiting_the_c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Parul Dave-Mukherji&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This paper sets out to revisit the Citrasūtra, a seminal section on painting from the Viṣṇudharmottarapurāṇa, in the light of key concerns around the cultural politics of art historiography, the śāstra-prayoga debate (Maxwell 1989, 5–15), and the related question of interpretative frameworks for studying early Indian art. The latter concern has lately come to the forefront in the context of post colonial studies and global art history. It is critical of intellectual parasitism (Dhareshwar 2015, 57–77) and pushes postcolonial thought to explore ‘native’ interpretative frames to study Indian art (Asher 2007, 12).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
